<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Muhammad Yaseen</title>
    <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Muhammad Yaseen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://myaseen208.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributions of Open Biomass Burning and Crop Straw Burning to Air Quality: Current Research Paradigm and Future Outlooks</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mehmood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mehmood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since open biomass burning (OBB) and open crop straw burning (OCSB) could pose a great risk to human health via altering the air quality, these practices have grabbed considerable attention from the scientific community and policymakers in recent years. In order to have a greater and deeper understanding of the contributions of both OBB and OCSB on air quality, a bibliometric analysis was performed using the Web of Science core collection to understand the research developments and future perspectives of these issues between 1991 and 2021. VOSviewer software 1.6.15 and R version 4.0.3 were employed to determine the annual scientific production trend and the role of countries, institutions, authors, and journal metrics network analysis. The findings showed that the interest in the study of OBB and OCSB pollution related to air quality has increased significantly over the last decade. A total of 1,021 publications were retrieved, with English as the most preferably used language. Among all documents, research articles were the most commonly appearing document type, and the researchers mainly emphasized environmental science, meteorology, atmospheric sciences, energy fuels, and environmental engineering fields. In terms of article analysis, Atmospheric Chemistry Physics, followed by Atmospheric Environment, was found to be the leading journal in this research domain, whereas the most frequently utilized keywords in the documents were biomass, biomass burning, and PM2.5. In terms of countries, the United States emerged as the leader with the highest publication rate, followed by China and India. The Chinese Academy of Sciences was ranked first in the list of most productive institutions, followed by the University of Montana and the US Forest Service. Based on the analysis, the finer spatial and temporal resolution and the characterization and understanding of the complex processes that are occurring in the atmosphere, such as clustering, oxidation, surface chemistry, and their impact on air quality, need to be explored in depth. Our research analysis can provide a baseline for future studies in air quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global research on the air quality status in response to the electrification of vehicles</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_bao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_bao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles (EVs) can substantially decrease atmospheric pollutant emissions, thereby improving air quality, decreasing global warming, and improving human health. In this study, we performed a comprehensive bibliometric analysis using Web of Science to understand the research developments and future perspectives in EVs between 1974 and 2021. The analysis of indicators such as research trends, publication growth, and keywords revealed that most research in the selected timeframe was focused on applying and optimizing the existing technologies of different types of EVs to decrease air pollution and mortality. The changes in air quality owing to such electrification received special attention, with approximately 441 publications preferably in the English language. Among all the retrieved documents, research articles were most common (n = 295; 66.89% of the global output), dominated by the research domains of environmental sciences, followed by energy fuels and transportation science technology. Journal analysis revealed that Sustainability (n = 19, 4.30%) was the leading journal, followed by Journal of Cleaner Production and Science of the Total Environment. The most frequently used keywords were &amp;ldquo;electric vehicles,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;air quality,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;air pollution.&amp;rdquo; The most highly impactful article was published by Jacobson et al. (2005) in Science, with 620 total citations and 38.82 average annual citations. Furthermore, the United States (n = 118; 26.75% of the global output) had the highest publication rate, followed by China and the United Kingdom. The leading institutions were Tsinghua University (n = 16; 3.62% of the global research output) in China, followed by the University of Michigan and Cornell University in the United States. The current analysis warrants more focus on comprehensive analysis employing transport and chemistry modeling and using the latest technology for long life and sustainable batteries. This study provides a basis for future studies on improving air quality through innovative work in the electrification of vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Pensioners and their Time Use: A Case Study of District Rahimyar Khan, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing.
All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.
Comparisons made were made showing that female nurses/
paramedics go through a tough time routine and time poverty as compared to their male counterpart which seems to be the cause of deterioration in this profession in the perspective of Pakistani society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel parent selection strategy for the development of drought-tolerant cotton cultivars</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chattha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chattha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drought is a devastating factor for crop production worldwide. Therefore, an experiment was conducted to study genetics for some agro-physiological traits in cotton under drought stress. The 13 parental cotton genotypes along with their 30 F1 hybrids were planted under normal and drought conditions. The mean performance of the genotypes was assessed through principal component and heat map analyses. The principal component analyses revealed 53.99 and 53.15% in the first two principal components of variability for normal and drought conditions, respectively. Heat map analysis revealed that three cotton genotypes i.e. FH-207 x NS-131, FH-207 x KZ-191 and S-15 x AA-703 attained higher values for all the traits except for canopy temperature under drought conditions. These crosses may proliferate to further filial generations to identify transgressive segregates for drought tolerance. The heritable differences of F??1 and mid-parent showed dominance and non-additive gene action under drought conditions. Heritable differences between F??1 and P??1 showed over dominance and partial dominance under drought conditions. Heritable differences between F??1 and P??2 indicated negative over dominance and partial dominance for all traits under drought conditions. Proline contents and the bolls per plant showed high heritability and genetic advance through additive gene action. Therefore, these two traits can be used as a means of selection in future breeding programmes of drought tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Time Use of Nurses and Paramedical Staff, Working in Public Hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan, Bahawalpur, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of
inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect
the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing.
All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were
included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the
population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random
sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.
Comparisons made were made showing that female nurses/
paramedics go through a tough time routine and time poverty as
compared to their male counterpart which seems to be the cause of
deterioration in this profession in the perspective of Pakistani
society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen application accelerates the downy mildew disease severity with leaf age in canola plants</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Downy mildew is a devastating disease of canola. Two years study was conducted to find the impact of different nitrogen levels on disease severity of downy mildew with respect to leaf age on canola plants in field conditions. Three nitrogen levels (11.50???Kg acre???1, 23???Kg acre???1 and 34.5???Kg acre???1) were applied in soil when plants were 40???days old. In control, 0???Kg acre???1 N was applied. The diseased leaves from the lower, middle and upper part of the plant were tagged and data were recorded after 10???days interval. Disease severity differed significantly between the two experimental years. A significant increase in disease severity was recorded with leaf age irrespective of the N concentration applied. Nitrogen concentrations significantly accelerated the disease severity with the increase of age. Maximum disease severity was recorded in 34.5???Kg acre???1 N applied 100???days old leaves in both experimental years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The level of Cry1Ac endotoxin and its efficacy against H. armigera in Bt cotton at large scale in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A biophysical survey was conducted in 15 cotton-growing districts of Pakistan. Four hundred cotton growers were approached and inquired about the production technology of Bt cotton. Further, 25 strip tests using combo strips (Cry1Ac, Cry2Ab, Vip3Aa and Cp4, EPSPS gene) were performed at each farmer&amp;rsquo;s field. Out of 10,000 total-tested samples, farmers claimed 9682 samples as Bt and 318 samples as non-Bt. After performing a strip test, 1009 and 87 samples were found false negative and false positive, respectively. Only 53 samples were found positive for Cry2Ab, 214 for EPSPS and none for Vip3Aa gene. Quantification of Cry endotoxin and bioassay studies were performed by taking leaves from upper, middle, and lower canopies, and fruiting parts at approximately 80 days after sowing from 89 varieties. Expression was highly variable among different canopies and fruiting parts. Moreover, Cry endotoxin expression and insect mortality varied significantly among varieties from 0.26 µg g???1 to 3.54 µg g???1 with mortality ranging from 28 to 97%, respectively. Highest Cry1Ac expression (3.54 µg g???1) and insect mortality (97%) were observed for variety FH-142 from DG Khan. Cry endotoxin expression varied significantly across various plant parts, i.e., IUB-13 variety from upper canopy documented 0.34 µg g???1 expression with 37% insect mortality in Layyah to 3.42 µg g???1 expression and 96% insect mortality from DG Khan. Lethal dose, LD95 (2.20 µg g???1) of Cry1Ac endotoxin was optimized for effective control of H. armigera. Our results provided evidence of practical resistance in H. armigera and way forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Fine and Coarse Rice Varieties for Nickel Accumulation and Growth Response at Different Levels of Nickel</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_fatma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_fatma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The differential growth response and nickel (Ni) accumulation by two rice varieties grown in Ni-contaminated soil are investigated. Soil is contaminated with Ni at different levels viz. control (0), 7, 15, 22, 30, and 38 mg kg???1 soil. Two rice varieties viz. Basmati-2000 (fine variety) and KSK-133 (coarse variety) are grown in pots containing Ni-contaminated soil. The plants are harvested at four growth stages with an interval of 15 days. Harvested plants are washed with distilled water to remove aerial deposition. Harvested plants are oven-dried, weighed, grinded, and digested with di-acid mixture. The digested samples are analyzed for Ni, zinc (Zn), and manganese (Mn) concentration. The results indicate that the maximum level of Ni (38 mg kg???1) inhibits the shoot and root growth. The maximum shoot and root dry weights are observed at lower level of Ni, that is, 7 mg kg???1. The concentration of Ni in plants increases with increasing Ni levels compared to control while the concentration of Zn and Mn decreases with increasing Ni levels. The maximum concentrations of all elements are recorded at the first harvest which gradually decrease in the subsequent harvests. It is concluded that Basmati-2000 is tolerant to Ni toxicity compared to KSK-133.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptability trials of sesame germplasm against macrophomina phaseolina (tassi) goid by using ammi biplot analysis in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_bashir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_bashir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current research was conducted to exploit the adaptability/resistance status of different sesame varieties/advanced lines of sesame germplasm against charcoal rot under different environmental conditions through AMMI Biplot analysis. Ten varieties/advanced lines of sesame viz., TS-5, 10003, 40009, 50009, 50011, 50022, 16001, 40004, Black Till and TH-6 were collected from Ayub Agricultural Research Institute (AARI), Faisalabad, Pakistan. The seeds of sesame varieties/advanced
lines were sown at six different locations namely Faisalabad, Toba Tek Singh, Piplan, Bhakhar, Mandi Baha Uddin and Bahawalpur with three replications under Randomized Complete Block Design. Statistical analysis was performed through R-statistical software, version 3.5.1. Combined analysis of variance was used to assess the level of significance whereas Genotype × Environment Interaction Table was used to separate means of data regarding disease incidence. Further, Additive Main Effects and Multiplicative Interaction (AMMI) Biplot was performed for stability analysis. Five sesame genotypes namely 40004, 40009, 50011, 50022, Black Till and TS-5, respectively, expressed resistant response at various locations with varying disease incidences whereas 50009 exhibited moderately susceptible response at Bhakkar, M.B. Din, Piplan and Toba Tek Singh with (36.76, 39.71, 40.95 and 46.98% disease incidences respectively. Likewise, two sesame advanced lines 10003
and 16001 expressed susceptible response at all locations with disease incidences of 64.547, 67.050, 66.75, 72.54, 77.38, 71.56% and 74.42, 72.03, 77.20, 77.27, 65.55, 69.06% correspondingly. It was concluded that resistant varieties are the most economical management strategy for farmers against charcoal rot of sesame.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the Effect of Water Deficit on Cotton Genotypes Using Agro-physiological and Biochemical Parameters</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_chattha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_chattha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To investigate the water-deficit tolerance, 45 cotton genotypes were grown under normal irrigation and water-deficit conditions for 2 years. Genotype x treatment x year interaction was determined for seed cotton yield, number of bolls, boll weight, chlorophyll fluorescence, proline contents, and total soluble proteins. Apart from proline levels, all traits showed a reduction under water-deficit conditions. The mean percentage reduction in seed cotton yield due to water deficit conditions was 52.83% and 42.19%, for number of bolls was 48.44% and 39.30%, for boll weight was reduced by 8.94% and 6.03% in 2013 and 2014 respectively. Reduction in chlorophyll fluorescence was 13.87% and 16.46% while soluble protein levels decreased by 25.57% and 21.09% during 2013 and 2014 respectively. For proline contents went up by 38.68% and 37.70% in 2013 and 2014 respectively. Relatively small changes in these parameters under water-deficit conditions were recorded for varieties FH-155, FH-207, FH-322, FH-329 IUB-13 and IUB-222 making these genotypes best suited for cultivation under water-deficit conditions. The positive correlation of seed cotton yield with proline contents and chlorophyll fluorescence under water-deficit condition indicates that these two traits can be considered to select cotton genotypes at early growth stages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors affecting C-section deliveries in Punjab</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_jabeen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_jabeen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study of Different Amendments on Amelioration of Saline-Sodic Soils Irrigated with Water Having Different EC: SAR Ratios</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_murtaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_murtaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Soil degradation affects soil properties such as structure, water retention, porosity, electrical conductivity (EC), sodium adsorption ratio (SAR), and soil flora and fauna. This study was conducted to evaluate the response of contrasting textured soils irrigated with water having different EC:SAR ratios along with amendments: gypsum (G), farm manure (FM), and mulch (M). Water of different qualities viz. EC 0.6 + SAR 6, EC 1.0 + SAR 12, EC 2.0 + SAR 18, and EC 4.0 + SAR 30 was used in different textured soils with G at 100% soil gypsum requirement, FM at 10 Mg ha âˆ’1 , and M as wheat straw was added on surface soil at 10 Mg ha âˆ’1 . Results revealed that the applied amendments in soils significantly decreased pH s and electrical conductivity (EC e ) of saturated paste and SAR. Four pore volumes of applied water with leaching fraction 0.75, 0.77, and 0.78 removed salts 3008, 4965, and 5048 kg ha âˆ’1 in loamy sand, silty clay loam, and sandy clay loam soils, respectively. First four irrigations with LF of 0.82, 0.79, 0.75, and 0.71, removed 5682, 5000, 3967, and 2941 kg ha âˆ’1 salts, respectively. The decreasing order for salt removal with amendments was FM &amp;gt; G &amp;gt; M &amp;gt; C with LF = 0.85, 0.84, 0.71, and 0.68, respectively. This study highlights a potential role of soil textures to initiate any mega program for reclamation of saline-sodic soils in the perspective of national development strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of training for in-hand manipulation on legibility of Urdu handwriting</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_jameel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_jameel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ffect of source of procurement of milk on the composition of milk supplied in Rawalpindi city</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ishaq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ishaq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential of Multivariate Analysis to Study the Impact of Cotton Leaf Curl Disease on Yield Traits</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_raza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_raza/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reclamation of wastewater containing Cu(II) using alginated Mentha spicata biomass</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_ansari/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_ansari/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMMI Biplot analysis for comparative evaluation of maize genotypes under different saline environments</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_aslam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_aslam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis and Forecasting of Water Reservoir in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_batool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_batool/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
