<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Muhammad Yaseen</title>
    <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Muhammad Yaseen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://myaseen208.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Protection for Persons with Disabilities in Pakistan: Current Scenario and Contribution of BISP</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2023_khalid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2023_khalid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, which pledges to ‚Äúleave no one behind,‚Äù emphasizes on promoting full and equal participation of all vulnerable and marginalized population segments in national development efforts, including persons with disabilities (PWDs). There is mounting evidence globally that differently abled people are disproportionately more vulnerable to both monetary and multi-dimensional poverty and require urgent support in terms of targeted social protection measures. The present paper presents a situation analysis and estimates of the population of PWDs across Pakistan, using different available data sources. It outlines the social protection framework for PWDs in Pakistan, with a special focus on support being extended to this population segment through the country‚Äôs largest social protection program the Benazir Income Support Programme (BISP) different BISP programs. It also provides recommendations for further increasing social protection coverage for this vulnerable population segment through developing synergies with other social protection programs for greater impact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Rain-Fed Conditions on Yield of Mash Bean Genepool by Using Augmented Design</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_yaseen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_yaseen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The augmented block design (ABD) is commonly used in breeding programs to evaluate the performance of large number of genotypes using non-replicated new test treatments and replicated check treatments. The purpose of this design is to determine which test treatment performs better than check treatments. The objective of this study is to identifying better genotype of Mash been than check treatment under rain feed condition of Pakistan. For this purpose, the data of 125 mash been genotypes included 5 check entries were analyzed. The experiment was conducted in augmented block design using 6 blocks in rain feed condition of Pakistan and data of different attribute were recorded. The analysis showed that the treatment effects (adjusted) are significant for all attributes. However, for all attribute other than the number of seeds/pod, the adjusted block effects are non-significant, indicating that the evaluated blocks are homogeneous. Only three principal components were considered, first component explained 33.85% of variation and 21.85%, 17.51% explained by PC2 and PC3 respectively for the first season whereas in the second season 33.62%, 23.43%, and 16. 86% variation described with respect to the first, second, and third principal components. First PC designated as a component of productivity, second as component of pod appearance while third designed as a component of physical appearances. All attributes showed significant and positive association with other attributes, only significantly negative association was among number of pods/plant and100-seeds weight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The impact of heat on kidney health: A PRISMA-compliant bibliometric analysis</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_al-bouwarthan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_al-bouwarthan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Background:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exposure to excessive heat can impact kidney health. Climate change is projected to aggravate this impact. An analysis of articles published between 1958 and 2021 was conducted to explore the progress of the research on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Methods:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study included a bibliometric analysis wherein Web of Science was used to generate a list of all published articles related to the impact of heat on kidney health. Basic information about the articles, such as titles, authors‚Äô names, keywords, and citations, were recorded and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Results:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A total of 226 published articles related to the impact of heat on kidney health were identified as of November 20, 2021. Most of these articles (93%) were published within the last decade. The United States was the most prominent country in terms of research productivity and collaboration. Researchers from the United States were well represented among the top 20 contributors of published articles on the study issue. The productivity of the top 20 authors varied between 6 and 32 articles each. A total of 25 common words used by the authors were identified. The most frequently used keywords were chronic kidney disease, heat stress, acute kidney injury, Mesoamerican nephropathy, and climate change. Keyword analysis revealed 3 distinct major research clusters in the existing scientific research on the impact of heat on kidney health: chronic kidney disease of unknown etiology, heat stress and renal physiology, and the effect of climate change on kidney health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on heat-related kidney injury has witnessed rapid development in recent decades, motivated by the emergence of chronic kidney disease of unknown etiology and climate change. Developing countries in hot regions must increase their productivity in this research area through international collaboration and partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Exploiting the potential of weedy rice as value added silage under different nitrogen levels and cutting intervals</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mubeen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mubeen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Weeds, often considered a ‚Äúmenace‚Äù are top-notch, adroit survivors having intrinsic value as source of biodiversity and various promising uses as bio-resource. Among other benefits, their use as feed/food source or raw material is still to be explored. Weedy rice (Oryza sativa f. spontanea) a conspecific of rice has rapid growth, ability to uptake more fertilizer and produce large biomass. Lot of efforts are done for its management but little is known about its nutritive value and utilization as feed source for livestock. Therefore, the present study was carried out at Agronomic Research Area, University of Agriculture, Faisalabad in 2017 and 2018 to optimize N level and harvesting time for improving growth and silage quality of weedy rice sown as sole crop. Treatments comprised of four N levels viz: 0, 100, 120 and 140 kg ha-1 and harvesting intervals viz. 15, 25 and 35 days after heading (DAH). Weedy rice harvested at different intervals after onset of heading stage was used for making silage and analysed for nutritive value. Results depicted that, maximum plant height, fertile tillers, panicle length, kernels per panicle and LA were obtained with 120 kg ha-1 N and harvesting at 25 DAH during both years, while NDF, ADF, cellulose, and hemicellulose were highest with no fertilizer. Crude protein was highest with N application at 120 kg ha-1 and harvesting at 25 DAH. Highest nitrogen contents in plants, plant biomass, WSC, ash and DM in silage were recorded with 140 kg ha-1 N when harvested at 35 DAH. Weedy rice harvested at 25 DAH with N application at 120 kg ha-1 seems to be better combination for rational use of nutrients, better productivity and improving most of the nutritive traits of whole crop weedy rice silage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributions of Open Biomass Burning and Crop Straw Burning to Air Quality: Current Research Paradigm and Future Outlooks</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mehmood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mehmood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since open biomass burning (OBB) and open crop straw burning (OCSB) could pose a great risk to human health via altering the air quality, these practices have grabbed considerable attention from the scientific community and policymakers in recent years. In order to have a greater and deeper understanding of the contributions of both OBB and OCSB on air quality, a bibliometric analysis was performed using the Web of Science core collection to understand the research developments and future perspectives of these issues between 1991 and 2021. VOSviewer software 1.6.15 and R version 4.0.3 were employed to determine the annual scientific production trend and the role of countries, institutions, authors, and journal metrics network analysis. The findings showed that the interest in the study of OBB and OCSB pollution related to air quality has increased significantly over the last decade. A total of 1,021 publications were retrieved, with English as the most preferably used language. Among all documents, research articles were the most commonly appearing document type, and the researchers mainly emphasized environmental science, meteorology, atmospheric sciences, energy fuels, and environmental engineering fields. In terms of article analysis, Atmospheric Chemistry Physics, followed by Atmospheric Environment, was found to be the leading journal in this research domain, whereas the most frequently utilized keywords in the documents were biomass, biomass burning, and PM2.5. In terms of countries, the United States emerged as the leader with the highest publication rate, followed by China and India. The Chinese Academy of Sciences was ranked first in the list of most productive institutions, followed by the University of Montana and the US Forest Service. Based on the analysis, the finer spatial and temporal resolution and the characterization and understanding of the complex processes that are occurring in the atmosphere, such as clustering, oxidation, surface chemistry, and their impact on air quality, need to be explored in depth. Our research analysis can provide a baseline for future studies in air quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global research on the air quality status in response to the electrification of vehicles</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_bao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_bao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles (EVs) can substantially decrease atmospheric pollutant emissions, thereby improving air quality, decreasing global warming, and improving human health. In this study, we performed a comprehensive bibliometric analysis using Web of Science to understand the research developments and future perspectives in EVs between 1974 and 2021. The analysis of indicators such as research trends, publication growth, and keywords revealed that most research in the selected timeframe was focused on applying and optimizing the existing technologies of different types of EVs to decrease air pollution and mortality. The changes in air quality owing to such electrification received special attention, with approximately 441 publications preferably in the English language. Among all the retrieved documents, research articles were most common (n = 295; 66.89% of the global output), dominated by the research domains of environmental sciences, followed by energy fuels and transportation science technology. Journal analysis revealed that Sustainability (n = 19, 4.30%) was the leading journal, followed by Journal of Cleaner Production and Science of the Total Environment. The most frequently used keywords were &amp;ldquo;electric vehicles,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;air quality,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;air pollution.&amp;rdquo; The most highly impactful article was published by Jacobson et al. (2005) in Science, with 620 total citations and 38.82 average annual citations. Furthermore, the United States (n = 118; 26.75% of the global output) had the highest publication rate, followed by China and the United Kingdom. The leading institutions were Tsinghua University (n = 16; 3.62% of the global research output) in China, followed by the University of Michigan and Cornell University in the United States. The current analysis warrants more focus on comprehensive analysis employing transport and chemistry modeling and using the latest technology for long life and sustainable batteries. This study provides a basis for future studies on improving air quality through innovative work in the electrification of vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Pensioners and their Time Use: A Case Study of District Rahimyar Khan, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing.
All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.
Comparisons made were made showing that female nurses/
paramedics go through a tough time routine and time poverty as compared to their male counterpart which seems to be the cause of deterioration in this profession in the perspective of Pakistani society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel parent selection strategy for the development of drought-tolerant cotton cultivars</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chattha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chattha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drought is a devastating factor for crop production worldwide. Therefore, an experiment was conducted to study genetics for some agro-physiological traits in cotton under drought stress. The 13 parental cotton genotypes along with their 30 F1 hybrids were planted under normal and drought conditions. The mean performance of the genotypes was assessed through principal component and heat map analyses. The principal component analyses revealed 53.99 and 53.15% in the first two principal components of variability for normal and drought conditions, respectively. Heat map analysis revealed that three cotton genotypes i.e. FH-207 x NS-131, FH-207 x KZ-191 and S-15 x AA-703 attained higher values for all the traits except for canopy temperature under drought conditions. These crosses may proliferate to further filial generations to identify transgressive segregates for drought tolerance. The heritable differences of F??1 and mid-parent showed dominance and non-additive gene action under drought conditions. Heritable differences between F??1 and P??1 showed over dominance and partial dominance under drought conditions. Heritable differences between F??1 and P??2 indicated negative over dominance and partial dominance for all traits under drought conditions. Proline contents and the bolls per plant showed high heritability and genetic advance through additive gene action. Therefore, these two traits can be used as a means of selection in future breeding programmes of drought tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Time Use of Nurses and Paramedical Staff, Working in Public Hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan, Bahawalpur, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of
inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect
the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing.
All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were
included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the
population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random
sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.
Comparisons made were made showing that female nurses/
paramedics go through a tough time routine and time poverty as
compared to their male counterpart which seems to be the cause of
deterioration in this profession in the perspective of Pakistani
society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen application accelerates the downy mildew disease severity with leaf age in canola plants</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Downy mildew is a devastating disease of canola. Two years study was conducted to find the impact of different nitrogen levels on disease severity of downy mildew with respect to leaf age on canola plants in field conditions. Three nitrogen levels (11.50???Kg acre???1, 23???Kg acre???1 and 34.5???Kg acre???1) were applied in soil when plants were 40???days old. In control, 0???Kg acre???1 N was applied. The diseased leaves from the lower, middle and upper part of the plant were tagged and data were recorded after 10???days interval. Disease severity differed significantly between the two experimental years. A significant increase in disease severity was recorded with leaf age irrespective of the N concentration applied. Nitrogen concentrations significantly accelerated the disease severity with the increase of age. Maximum disease severity was recorded in 34.5???Kg acre???1 N applied 100???days old leaves in both experimental years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The level of Cry1Ac endotoxin and its efficacy against H. armigera in Bt cotton at large scale in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A biophysical survey was conducted in 15 cotton-growing districts of Pakistan. Four hundred cotton growers were approached and inquired about the production technology of Bt cotton. Further, 25 strip tests using combo strips (Cry1Ac, Cry2Ab, Vip3Aa and Cp4, EPSPS gene) were performed at each farmer&amp;rsquo;s field. Out of 10,000 total-tested samples, farmers claimed 9682 samples as Bt and 318 samples as non-Bt. After performing a strip test, 1009 and 87 samples were found false negative and false positive, respectively. Only 53 samples were found positive for Cry2Ab, 214 for EPSPS and none for Vip3Aa gene. Quantification of Cry endotoxin and bioassay studies were performed by taking leaves from upper, middle, and lower canopies, and fruiting parts at approximately 80 days after sowing from 89 varieties. Expression was highly variable among different canopies and fruiting parts. Moreover, Cry endotoxin expression and insect mortality varied significantly among varieties from 0.26 µg g???1 to 3.54 µg g???1 with mortality ranging from 28 to 97%, respectively. Highest Cry1Ac expression (3.54 µg g???1) and insect mortality (97%) were observed for variety FH-142 from DG Khan. Cry endotoxin expression varied significantly across various plant parts, i.e., IUB-13 variety from upper canopy documented 0.34 µg g???1 expression with 37% insect mortality in Layyah to 3.42 µg g???1 expression and 96% insect mortality from DG Khan. Lethal dose, LD95 (2.20 µg g???1) of Cry1Ac endotoxin was optimized for effective control of H. armigera. Our results provided evidence of practical resistance in H. armigera and way forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2014Wm: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2014 Women Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014wm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014wm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2014 Women (age 15-49 years) questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Fine and Coarse Rice Varieties for Nickel Accumulation and Growth Response at Different Levels of Nickel</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_fatma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_fatma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The differential growth response and nickel (Ni) accumulation by two rice varieties grown in Ni-contaminated soil are investigated. Soil is contaminated with Ni at different levels viz. control (0), 7, 15, 22, 30, and 38 mg kg???1 soil. Two rice varieties viz. Basmati-2000 (fine variety) and KSK-133 (coarse variety) are grown in pots containing Ni-contaminated soil. The plants are harvested at four growth stages with an interval of 15 days. Harvested plants are washed with distilled water to remove aerial deposition. Harvested plants are oven-dried, weighed, grinded, and digested with di-acid mixture. The digested samples are analyzed for Ni, zinc (Zn), and manganese (Mn) concentration. The results indicate that the maximum level of Ni (38 mg kg???1) inhibits the shoot and root growth. The maximum shoot and root dry weights are observed at lower level of Ni, that is, 7 mg kg???1. The concentration of Ni in plants increases with increasing Ni levels compared to control while the concentration of Zn and Mn decreases with increasing Ni levels. The maximum concentrations of all elements are recorded at the first harvest which gradually decrease in the subsequent harvests. It is concluded that Basmati-2000 is tolerant to Ni toxicity compared to KSK-133.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of repeated pollination on tomato hybrid seed yield under field conditions</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chishti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chishti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hybrid seed yield in tomato is strongly influenced by temperature variations. In this regard a study was conducted to estimate the effect of repeated pollination on fruit setting percentage and number of seeds / fruit under variable natural temperature during the year 2017-18 at Vegetable Research Institute, Ayub Agricultural Research Institute (AARI), Faisalabad, Pakistan. The female parent of commercial indeterminate tomato hybrid (Saandal F1) was emasculated. Pollination was done once (T1), twice (T2) and thrice (T3) keeping the interval of 24 hours between each pollination on daily basis and continued for 22 days under field conditions. Analysis of data revealed that there were significant differences among treatments, temperatures and treatment ◊ temperature interaction for both traits. At the temperature range of 17∞C - 28.6∞C, there was considerable increase in fruit setting in T2 (30.2 %) and T3 (37.7 %) as compared to T1. Linear model was used to explain the behavior of T1. However, for T2 and T3, second degree polynomial model was used. Graphic representation also revealed increase in fruit setting percentage and number of seeds/fruit in to T2 and T3 treatments. However, at higher temperature range of 30∞C - 33∞C, T2 and T3 responded negatively with the reduction of -7.0 and -23.1% in fruit setting, respectively as compared to T1. For number of seeds/fruit, T2 and T3 showed 50.2 and 58.7% increase, respectively as compared to T1 at temperature range of 17∞C - 28.6∞C. However, at 30∞C - 33∞C temperature range, T2 exhibited 50.4% increase over T1 whereas; T3 showed decline in number of seeds/fruit (-14.0 %) in comparison with T1. It was concluded that at low temperature range (17∞C-28.6∞C) two times pollination (T2) could be more effective for traits that ultimately contribute in higher seed yield.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DiallelAnalysisR: Diallel Analysis with R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_diallelanalysisr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_diallelanalysisr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Performs Diallel Analysis with R using Griffing&amp;rsquo;s and Hayman&amp;rsquo;s approaches. Four different Methods (1: Method-I (Parents + F1&amp;rsquo;s + reciprocals); 2: Method-II (Parents and one set of F1&amp;rsquo;s); 3: Method-III (One set of F1&amp;rsquo;s and reciprocals); 4: Method-IV (One set of F1&amp;rsquo;s only)) and two Models (1: Fixed Effects Model; 2: Random Effects Model) can be applied using Griffing&amp;rsquo;s approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan Education Statistics 2017-18</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_shah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_shah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;report-at-a-glance&#34;&gt;Report at a Glance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i-analysis-of-education-statistics&#34;&gt;Part I: Analysis of Education Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part of the report includes the following four chapters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1-introduction&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter gives a brief introduction of education system of the country. It also gives the structure of education sector from Pre-Primary to Higher Secondary level in Pakistan. It highlights how Education Management Information System (EMIS) is working in Pakistan along with different data sources used for compilation of this report. The limitations of the data collection for this publication are also given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-2-education-statistics-an-overview&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: Education Statistics: An Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter highlights the basic educational statistics based on number of institutions, student enrolment and number of teachers with respect to gender, education categories, public/private &amp;amp;
provinces/regions divide for these parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-3-educational-trends&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: Educational Trends&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter compares last five years educational data for public/private sector with respect to gender, education categories &amp;amp; provinces/regions. Last five years trends for number of institutions, student enrolment &amp;amp; number of teachers in all provinces/regions of the country are highlighted. Change in gross enrolment &amp;amp; adjusted net enrolment ratios are also depicted graphically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-4-effectiveness-of-the-education-system&#34;&gt;Chapter 4: Effectiveness of the Education System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter focuses on quality of education which is also a major concern for education planners and managers, therefore, the key indicators used to measure quality of education system are discussed using important indicators like Survival Rate, Pupil-Teacher, Pupil-School and Teacher-School Ratios. In addition the availability of different physical facilities in the education system are also highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-ii-education-statistics&#34;&gt;Part II: Education Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part gives detailed education statistics data in the form of tables. At the start of each chapter in Part-II a list of data sources and explanatory notes for the tables are given for the benefit of the user of PES 2017-18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-5-key-education-indicators&#34;&gt;Chapter 5: Key Education Indicators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter gives data tables for Survival, Effective Transition &amp;amp; Literacy Rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-6-institutions&#34;&gt;Chapter 6: Institutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data tables depicting information about formal &amp;amp; non-formal education institutions of all the Provinces/Regions are given in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-7-enrolment&#34;&gt;Chapter 7: Enrolment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data tables relating to student enrolment in different education categories are given in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-8-teachers&#34;&gt;Chapter 8: Teachers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics about teaching staff serving in different sectors of education &amp;amp; in different provinces/regions are presented in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-9-physical-facilities&#34;&gt;Chapter 9: Physical Facilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data related to availability of physical facilities in educational institutions in public sector is given in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High resolution Bayesain Spatio-Temporal precipitation modelling in Pakistan for the appraisal of trends</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_maqsood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_maqsood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Appraisal of spatio-temporal variability of precipitation is important for studying climate change and managing water resources. In this article, data on monsoon precipitation of Pakistan are analyzed for spatio-temporal interpolation using two hierarchical Bayesian spatio-temporal methods which are DLM and AR models. The precipitation records along with three meteorological covariates (temperature, wind speed and humidity) are collected from 53 stations for the years 2000-2008. Initially, we simulated four data sets using AR model with four levels of autoregressive parameter  = (0.2, 0.5, 0.7, 0.9) and both models are fitted. It is observed that for the larger values of, DLM gives better results as compared to AR model while AR model performs better for the smaller values of. The estimated value of for precipitation data in the whole study domain is 0.02 which supports AR model for final spatio-temporal mapping. For real data application, data of 45 locations are used for modeling while data of 8 locations have been set aside for cross validation and we use hyper-parameters  and  of inverse gamma distribution as variance parameters for AR and DLM models. The prediction performances of both models have been examined using Bayesian and non-Bayesian model choice criteria. The predictive inferences are drawn using MCMC algorithm. Prediction plots show that the areas that lie between 32o-36o east latitude and 70o -74o north longitude are high precipitation areas in Pakistan and are helpful in the identification of homogeneous climate zones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eda4treeR: Experimental Design and Analysis for Tree Improvement.</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_eda4treer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_eda4treer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data sets and R Codes for Williams, E.R., Matheson, A.C. and Harwood, C.E. (2002). Experimental Design and Analysis for Tree Improvement, CSIRO Publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptability trials of sesame germplasm against macrophomina phaseolina (tassi) goid by using ammi biplot analysis in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_bashir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_bashir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current research was conducted to exploit the adaptability/resistance status of different sesame varieties/advanced lines of sesame germplasm against charcoal rot under different environmental conditions through AMMI Biplot analysis. Ten varieties/advanced lines of sesame viz., TS-5, 10003, 40009, 50009, 50011, 50022, 16001, 40004, Black Till and TH-6 were collected from Ayub Agricultural Research Institute (AARI), Faisalabad, Pakistan. The seeds of sesame varieties/advanced
lines were sown at six different locations namely Faisalabad, Toba Tek Singh, Piplan, Bhakhar, Mandi Baha Uddin and Bahawalpur with three replications under Randomized Complete Block Design. Statistical analysis was performed through R-statistical software, version 3.5.1. Combined analysis of variance was used to assess the level of significance whereas Genotype ◊ Environment Interaction Table was used to separate means of data regarding disease incidence. Further, Additive Main Effects and Multiplicative Interaction (AMMI) Biplot was performed for stability analysis. Five sesame genotypes namely 40004, 40009, 50011, 50022, Black Till and TS-5, respectively, expressed resistant response at various locations with varying disease incidences whereas 50009 exhibited moderately susceptible response at Bhakkar, M.B. Din, Piplan and Toba Tek Singh with (36.76, 39.71, 40.95 and 46.98% disease incidences respectively. Likewise, two sesame advanced lines 10003
and 16001 expressed susceptible response at all locations with disease incidences of 64.547, 67.050, 66.75, 72.54, 77.38, 71.56% and 74.42, 72.03, 77.20, 77.27, 65.55, 69.06% correspondingly. It was concluded that resistant varieties are the most economical management strategy for farmers against charcoal rot of sesame.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Observed social support and willingness for the treatment of patients with schizophrenia</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_jameel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_jameel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt; Schizophrenia is a mental disorder that causes the social breakdown of relationships with others. Patients with schizophrenia interpret reality and verbal communication in an abnormal way. They experience great difficulty in building and maintaining of social relationships within society. They also experience barriers in communication and motivation that hinder their readiness for treatment. The willingness of patients with schizophrenia to be treated improves mental illness, social support and other health-related issues. The main purpose of this study was to explore the relationship between social support and willingness for treatment in patients with Schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; The qualitative research approach was used to solicit and capture more in-depth information from participants. The research design was phenomenological in nature. A cross-sectional survey method was employed. The sample consisted of twenty female patients diagnosed with schizophrenia, seven psychiatrists, and seven psychologists. A semi-structured interview guide was developed to collect the data. The interview guide covered three themes. The first theme included four questions for patients with schizophrenia. The second theme consisted of six questions for the psychiatrists and the third theme included two questions for the psychologists. Interview data were analysed through frame workanalysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; The results of the study showed that social support plays an essential role in the improvement of patients with schizophrenia. Psychiatrists with the help of medication and therapies reduce the negativity and anxiety level of patients and motivate patients to accept treatment. Through counseling, psychologists help patients with schizophrenia build social skills such as the ability to engage in eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; It is revealed that the social support is closely related to the willingness for treatment in patients with schizophrenia. Therefore, social support is recommended in the course of treatment of patients with schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the Effect of Water Deficit on Cotton Genotypes Using Agro-physiological and Biochemical Parameters</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_chattha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_chattha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To investigate the water-deficit tolerance, 45 cotton genotypes were grown under normal irrigation and water-deficit conditions for 2 years. Genotype x treatment x year interaction was determined for seed cotton yield, number of bolls, boll weight, chlorophyll fluorescence, proline contents, and total soluble proteins. Apart from proline levels, all traits showed a reduction under water-deficit conditions. The mean percentage reduction in seed cotton yield due to water deficit conditions was 52.83% and 42.19%, for number of bolls was 48.44% and 39.30%, for boll weight was reduced by 8.94% and 6.03% in 2013 and 2014 respectively. Reduction in chlorophyll fluorescence was 13.87% and 16.46% while soluble protein levels decreased by 25.57% and 21.09% during 2013 and 2014 respectively. For proline contents went up by 38.68% and 37.70% in 2013 and 2014 respectively. Relatively small changes in these parameters under water-deficit conditions were recorded for varieties FH-155, FH-207, FH-322, FH-329 IUB-13 and IUB-222 making these genotypes best suited for cultivation under water-deficit conditions. The positive correlation of seed cotton yield with proline contents and chlorophyll fluorescence under water-deficit condition indicates that these two traits can be considered to select cotton genotypes at early growth stages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SupMZ: Detecting Structural Change with Heteroskedasticity</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_supmz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_supmz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Calculates the sup MZ value to detect the unknown structural break points under Heteroskedasticity as given in Ahmed et al. (2017)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2018mm: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Maternal Mortality Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018mm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Maternal Mortality questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan. The results of the present survey are critically important for the purposes of Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) monitoring, as the survey produces information on 32 global Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) indicators. The data was collected from 53,840 households selected at the second stage with systematic random sampling out of a sample of 2,692 clusters selected using probability proportional to size sampling. Six questionnaires were used in the survey: (1) a household questionnaire to collect basic demographic information on all de jure household members (usual residents), the household, and the dwelling; (2) a water quality testing questionnaire administered in three households in each cluster of the sample; (3) a questionnaire for individual women administered in each household to all women age 15-49 years; (4) a questionnaire for individual men administered in every second household to all men age 15-49 years; (5) an under-5 questionnaire, administered to mothers (or caretakers) of all children under 5 living in the household; and (6) a questionnaire for children age 5-17 years, administered to the mother (or caretaker) of one randomly selected child age 5-17 years living in the household (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&#34;&gt;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2018mn: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Men Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018mn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018mn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The PakPMICS2018mn provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Men questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan. The results of the present survey are critically important for the purposes of Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) monitoring, as the survey produces information on 32 global Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) indicators. The data was collected from 53,840 households selected at the second stage with systematic random sampling out of a sample of 2,692 clusters selected using Probability Proportional to size sampling. Six questionnaires were used in the survey:
(1) a household questionnaire to collect basic demographic information on all de jure household members (usual residents), the household, and the dwelling;
(2) a water quality testing questionnaire administered in three households in each cluster of the sample;
(3) a questionnaire for individual women administered in each household to all women age 15-49 years;
(4) a questionnaire for individual men administered in every second household to all men age 15-49 years;
(5) an under-5 questionnaire, administered to mothers (or caretakers) of all children under 5 living in the household; and
(6) a questionnaire for children age 5-17 years, administered to the mother (or caretaker) of one randomly selected child age 5-17 years living in the household.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2018fs: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Children Age 5-17 Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018fs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Children Age 5-17 questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan. The results of the present survey are critically important for the purposes of Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) monitoring, as the survey produces information on 32 global Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) indicators. The data was collected from 53,840 households selected at the second stage with systematic random sampling out of a sample of 2,692 clusters selected using probability proportional to size sampling. Six questionnaires were used in the survey: (1) a household questionnaire to collect basic demographic information on all de jure household members (usual residents), the household, and the dwelling; (2) a water quality testing questionnaire administered in three households in each cluster of the sample; (3) a questionnaire for individual women administered in each household to all women age 15-49 years; (4) a questionnaire for individual men administered in every second household to all men age 15-49 years; (5) an under-5 questionnaire, administered to mothers (or caretakers) of all children under 5 living in the household; and (6) a questionnaire for children age 5-
17 years, administered to the mother (or caretaker) of one randomly selected child age 5-
17 years living in the household (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&#34;&gt;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2018hh: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Household Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018hh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018hh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Household questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan. The results of the present survey are critically important for the purposes of Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) monitoring, as the survey produces information on 32 global Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) indicators. The data was collected from 53,840 households selected at the second stage with systematic random sampling out of a sample of 2,692 clusters selected using probability proportional to size sampling. Six questionnaires were used in the survey: (1) a household questionnaire to collect basic demographic information on all de jure household members (usual residents), the household, and the dwelling; (2) a water quality testing questionnaire administered in three households in each cluster of the sample; (3) a questionnaire for individual women administered in each household to all women age 15-49 years; (4) a questionnaire for individual men administered in every second household to all men age 15-49 years; (5) an under-5 questionnaire, administered to mothers (or caretakers) of all children under 5 living in the household; and (6) a questionnaire for children age 5-17 years, administered to the mother (or caretaker) of one randomly selected child age 5-17 years living in the household (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&#34;&gt;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2018bh: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Birth History of Children Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018bh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_pakpmics2018bh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2017-18 Household questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan. The results of the present survey are critically important for the purposes of SDG monitoring, as the survey produces information on 32 global SDG indicators. The data was collected from 53,840 households selected at the second stage with systematic random sampling out of a sample of 2,692 clusters selected using Probability Proportional to size sampling. Six questionnaires were used in the survey: (1) a household questionnaire to collect basic demographic information on all de jure household members (usual residents), the household, and the dwelling; (2) a water quality testing questionnaire administered in three households in each cluster of the sample; (3) a questionnaire for individual women administered in each household to all women age 15-49 years; (4) a questionnaire for individual men administered in every second household to all men age 15-49 years; (5) an under-5 questionnaire, administered to mothers (or caretakers) of all children under 5 living in the household; and (6) a questionnaire for children age 5-17 years, administered to the mother (or caretaker) of one randomly selected child age 5-17 years living in the household (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&#34;&gt;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>agriTutorial: Tutorial Analysis of Some Agricultural Experiments</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_agritutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_agritutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Example software for the analysis of data from designed experiments, especially agricultural crop experiments. The basics of the analysis of designed experiments are discussed using real examples from agricultural field trials. A range of statistical methods using a range of R statistical packages are exemplified . The experimental data is made available as separate data sets for each example and the R analysis code is made available as example code. The example code can be readily extended, as required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dmai: Divisia Monetary Aggregates Index</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_dmai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_dmai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Functions to calculate Divisia monetary aggregates index as given in Barnett, W. A. (1980)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of genetic variability in mustard against alternaria leaf spot disease through natural field conditions</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_bashir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2019_bashir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The research was conducted for the source of resistance against Alternaria leaf spot disease of brassica. In the current research, ten varieties/ advanced lines were evaluated in 2016-17 and 2017-18 against this disease using Randomized Complete Block Design (RCBD) at the experimental research area of Oilseeds Research Institute, Ayub Agricultural Research Institute Faisalabad. During 2016, three advanced lines (RBN-13017, RBN-13022 and RBN-13029) exhibited moderately resistant response with 22.33%, 18.42% and 13.76% disease incidence respectively under rating 2 whereas two advanced lines namely KN-294 (34.56%) and 14CBN009 (42.99%) expressed a moderately susceptible response (rating 3). Similarly, four advanced lines/ varieties showed susceptible response with (66.54%), (54.28%), (64.77%) and (60.12) percent disease incidence while KJ-159 was used as spreader that expressed highly susceptible response with 92.14 % disease incidence. During 2017-18 four varieties/ advanced lines namely KN-279, 14CBN001, Faisal Canola and Rohi Sarson exhibited susceptible response with (68.84%), (56.38%), (66.97%) and (58.22) percent disease incidence (rating 4) whereas two advanced lines such as KN-294 (31.86%) and 14CBN009 (40.09%) showed moderately susceptible response (rating 3). Likewise, three advanced lines exhibited moderately resistant response with 24.63%, 19.82% and 12.06% disease incidence respectively under rating 2. It was concluded that source of resistance is the most economical management strategy for the farmers against Alternaria Leaf Spot Disease of brassica.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>qccrs: Quality Control Charts under Repetitive Sampling</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_qccrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_qccrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Functions to calculate Average Sample Numbers (ASN), Average Run Length (ARL1) and value of k, k1 and k2 for quality control charts under repetitive sampling as given in Aslam et al. (2014)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors affecting C-section deliveries in Punjab</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_jabeen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_jabeen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rgsp: Repetitive Group Sampling Plan Based on Cpk</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_rgsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_rgsp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Functions to calculate Sample Number and Average Sample Number for Repetitive Group Sampling Plan Based on Cpk as given in Aslam et al. (2013).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>baystability: Bayesian Stability Analysis of Genotype by Environment Interaction (GEI).</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_bayestability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_bayestability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Performs general Bayesian estimation method of linear-bilinear models for genotype ◊ environment interaction. The method is explained in Perez-Elizalde, S., Jarquin, D., and Crossa, J. (2011) (&lt;a href=&#34;doi:10.1007/s13253-011-0063-9&#34;&gt;doi:10.1007/s13253-011-0063-9&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stability: Stability Analysis of Genotype by Environment Interaction (GEI)</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_stability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Functionalities to perform Stability Analysis of Genotype by Environment Interaction (GEI) to identify superior and stable genotypes under diverse environments. It performs Eberhart &amp;amp; Russel&amp;rsquo;s ANOVA (1966) (&lt;a href=&#34;doi:10.2135/cropsci1966.0011183X000600010011x&#34;&gt;doi:10.2135/cropsci1966.0011183X000600010011x&lt;/a&gt;), Finlay and Wilkinson (1963) Joint Linear Regression (&lt;a href=&#34;doi:10.1071/AR9630742&#34;&gt;doi:10.1071/AR9630742&lt;/a&gt;), Wricke (1962, 1964) Ecovalence, Shukla&amp;rsquo;s stability variance parameter (1972) (&lt;a href=&#34;doi:10.1038/hdy.1972.87&#34;&gt;doi:10.1038/hdy.1972.87&lt;/a&gt;) and Kang&amp;rsquo;s (1991) (&lt;a href=&#34;doi:10.2134/agronj1991.00021962008300010037x&#34;&gt;doi:10.2134/agronj1991.00021962008300010037x&lt;/a&gt;) simultaneous selection for high yielding and stable parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ppcSpatial: Spatial Analysis of Pakistan Population Census</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ppcspatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ppcspatial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spatial Analysis for exploration of Pakistan Population Census 2017 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbscensus.gov.pk/&#34;&gt;http://www.pbscensus.gov.pk/&lt;/a&gt;). It uses data from R package &amp;lsquo;PakPC2017&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Comparison of Partial Least Squares, Principal Component and Ridge Regression in the presence of multicollinearity</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_emperical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_emperical/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors affecting C-section deliveries in Punjab</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_factors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gvcR: Genotypic Variance Components</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_gvcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_gvcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Functionalities to compute model based genetic components i.e. genotypic variance, phenotypic variance and heritability for given traits of different genotypes from replicated data using methodology explained by Burton, G. W. &amp;amp; Devane, E. H. (1953) (&lt;a href=&#34;doi:10.2134/agronj1953.00021962004500100005x&#34;&gt;doi:10.2134/agronj1953.00021962004500100005x&lt;/a&gt;) and Allard, R.W. (2010, ISBN:8126524154).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPC2017: Pakistan Population Census 2017</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_pakpc2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_pakpc2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data sets and functions for exploration of Pakistan Population Census 2017 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbscensus.gov.pk/&#34;&gt;http://www.pbscensus.gov.pk/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study of Different Amendments on Amelioration of Saline-Sodic Soils Irrigated with Water Having Different EC: SAR Ratios</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_murtaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_murtaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Soil degradation affects soil properties such as structure, water retention, porosity, electrical conductivity (EC), sodium adsorption ratio (SAR), and soil flora and fauna. This study was conducted to evaluate the response of contrasting textured soils irrigated with water having different EC:SAR ratios along with amendments: gypsum (G), farm manure (FM), and mulch (M). Water of different qualities viz. EC 0.6 + SAR 6, EC 1.0 + SAR 12, EC 2.0 + SAR 18, and EC 4.0 + SAR 30 was used in different textured soils with G at 100% soil gypsum requirement, FM at 10 Mg ha ‚àí1 , and M as wheat straw was added on surface soil at 10 Mg ha ‚àí1 . Results revealed that the applied amendments in soils significantly decreased pH s and electrical conductivity (EC e ) of saturated paste and SAR. Four pore volumes of applied water with leaching fraction 0.75, 0.77, and 0.78 removed salts 3008, 4965, and 5048 kg ha ‚àí1 in loamy sand, silty clay loam, and sandy clay loam soils, respectively. First four irrigations with LF of 0.82, 0.79, 0.75, and 0.71, removed 5682, 5000, 3967, and 2941 kg ha ‚àí1 salts, respectively. The decreasing order for salt removal with amendments was FM &amp;gt; G &amp;gt; M &amp;gt; C with LF = 0.85, 0.84, 0.71, and 0.68, respectively. This study highlights a potential role of soil textures to initiate any mega program for reclamation of saline-sodic soils in the perspective of national development strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of training for in-hand manipulation on legibility of Urdu handwriting</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_jameel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_jameel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ffect of source of procurement of milk on the composition of milk supplied in Rawalpindi city</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ishaq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ishaq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSLM2015: Pakistan Social and Living Standards Measurement Survey 2014-15</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_pslm2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_pslm2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data and statistics of Pakistan Social and Living Standards Measurement (PSLM) survey 2014-15 from Pakistan Bureau of Statistics (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.gov.pk/&#34;&gt;http://www.pbs.gov.pk/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VetResearchLMM: Linear Mixed Models- An Introduction with Applications in Veterinary Research.</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_vetresearchlmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_vetresearchlmm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R Codes and Datasets for Duchateau, L. and Janssen, P. and Rowlands, G. J. (1998). Linear Mixed Models. An Introduction with applications in Veterinary Research. International Livestock Research Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of physical form of feed and addition of live yeast culture (saccharomyces cerevisiae) on the growth performance and carcass traits of beetal male kids under high input feeding system</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_effect/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2014Ch: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2014 Child Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014ch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and functions for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2014 Child questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&#34;&gt;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2014HH: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2014 Household Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014hh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014hh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2014 Household questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&#34;&gt;http://www.mics.unicef.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PakPMICS2014HL: Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) 2014 Household Listing Questionnaire Data for Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014hl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_pakpmics2014hl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Provides data set and function for exploration of Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2014 Household Listing questionnaire data for Punjab, Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential of Multivariate Analysis to Study the Impact of Cotton Leaf Curl Disease on Yield Traits</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_raza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_raza/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMMI Biplot analysis for comparative evaluation of maize genotypes under different saline environments</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_aslam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_aslam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis and Forecasting of Water Reservoir in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_batool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_batool/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StroupGLMM: R Codes and Datasets for Generalized Linear Mixed Models: Modern Concepts, Methods and Applications by Walter W. Stroup</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_stroupglmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_stroupglmm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R Codes and Datasets for Stroup, W. W. (2012). Generalized Linear Mixed Models: Modern Concepts, Methods and Applications, CRC Press.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Investigation of Economic Variables of Pakistan by Using Autoregressive Distributed LAG Model</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_imperial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_imperial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this research two main techniques of time series analysis, Co-integration and Autoregressive Distributed Lag (ARDL) model were discussed with the advantages of one technique over the other. This study used to investigate the relationship between five economic variables of Pakistan by using monthly data for the period 1975 to 2015. ARDL model was used to study the relationship between Exchange Rate on Consumer Price Index, Money Supply, Imports and Exports. This work inspects the Short Run (SR) dynamic and Long Run (LR) relationship with the aid of autoregressive distributed lag (ARDL) model. First apply Augmented Dicky-Fuller (ADF) test and Phillips-Peron (PP) Test for checking the stationary of variables. The second step was ARDL-Bound Test and it concluded that variables have long run relation with each other. After ARDL-Bound Test next step was selection of lag length for ARDL model. The diagnostic test inspected that model is good to fit. The ARDL model exposed significant and non-significant long run relation. The coefficient of ECM (-1) indicates how much of the disequilibrium in the short-run was fixed (eliminated) in the long-run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the In-control Robustness of Progressive Mean Control Chart</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_assesing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_assesing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Approach: An Alternative of Additive Main effect and Multiplicative Interaction (AMMI) model for Genotype-by-Environment Interaction (GEI)</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_bayesianapproach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_bayesianapproach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian network for modeling relationships among variables of neonatal sepsis</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_bayesian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_bayesian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Tool for the Assessment of English and Urdu Handwriting</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_development/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drought Forecasting using Seasonal Autoregressive Integrated Moving Average Models and Artificial Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_drought/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_drought/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impulse Response Function Analysis: An Application to Macroeconomic Data of Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_impulse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_impulse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Impulse response function (IRF) is increasingly common in financial markets; it is significantly related to policy changes of Government or the firm. An IRF of any dynamic model is its reaction to some external fluctuations emerged with brief input signals over time. It is a way to examine and evaluate the impact of external shocks. To make a comprehensive view of Pakistan&amp;rsquo;s macroeconomy, six typical macroeconomic indicators focused for analysis. In this study the impact of one variable to all other variables with respect to external shocks has valued description with the help of VAR model. By the help of IRF it can be concluded that exchange rate, Import rate, export rate and money supply in Pakistan have strong relation between themand show a considerable reaction in future for the impulses occur in each other so the model of these four variables have sound predictive validity and used for better forecast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpolating CD Metal in Soil Using Spatial Techniques in Metropolis Areas of Faisalabad</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_interpolating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_interpolating/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Equation Modeling to study the relationship of Cotton fiber traits</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_structural/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_structural/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis and Forecasting of Water Reservoir in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_forecasting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In water resource management daily flow to the reservoir is most important factor, in this study the daily flow to the reservoir as well as upstream has been forecast by different models. Autoregressive Integrated Moving Average (ARIMA) and Autoregressive Moving Average (ARMA) models has been used to forecast daily flow of different dams and linked canals in Pakistan. Application in practical science ARIMA model plays an important role. Both ARIMA and ARMA model has been used to compare the capability of autoregressive forecast of daily dam reservoir inflow. Forecast accuracy of Tarbela Dam reservoir inflow has been increased if we increase the number of parameter in ARMA and ARIMA models. To forecast Dam reservoir inflow polynomial for ARMA and ARIMA models was derived up to four and six parameter. Root mean square error concludes that ARIMA model can be used to forecast the level of water for different rivers in Pakistan with less error than ARMA model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grain Cadmium concentration decreased in Rice (Oryza sativa L.) while managing different Water Regimes</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_grain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_grain/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reclamation of wastewater containing Cu(II) using alginated Mentha spicata biomass</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_ansari/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_ansari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The task of looking for new and potentially feasible metal biosorbents has a wide scope. In the present work, optimization of thermodynamic and kinetic parameters has been carried out for the removal of Cu(II) from aqueous solution using Mentha spicata distillation waste (native and alginated) biomass. M. spicata distillation waste biomass was efficiently used for toxic Cu(II) removal under optimized conditions of pH, biosorbent dose, biosorbent size, initial metal concentration, contact time, and desorption. Langmuir adsorption isotherm and
pseudo-second-order kinetic models fitted well to Cu(II) sorption by native and alginated M. spicata distillation waste biomass. The significant changes in the vibrational frequencies of Fourier transform infrared spectra implicated that carboxylic, carbonyl, and nitrile groups
played vital role during Cu(II) biosorption process. A new peak at 1,735 cm???1 corresponding to the -C=O groups appeared, suggesting that -C-O groups oxidized to -C=O groups during biosorption process. Alginated M. spicata distillation waste biomass exhibited a very high Cu(II) adsorption capacity (176.96 mg/g).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yield Losses in Chickpea (Cicer arietinum L.) with Varying Densities of Euphorbia dracunculoides L.</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_tanveer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_tanveer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of economic threshold level and growth habits of weeds in chickpea is essential to implement timely, effective, and economical weed control treatments. The effect of weed density on growth and yield performance in chickpea using dragon spurge as a test weed was investigated for 2 consecutive yr. Dragon spurge density levels of 5, 10, 15, 20, 25, 30, 35, and 40 plants m???2 were compared with weed-free plots. Each increment in densities of dragon spurge from 5 to 40 plants m???2 reduced plant height, number of fruits, seeds, and dry weight per plant. Chickpea grain yield losses varied between 1 to 63% with dragon spurge density ranging from 5 to 40 plants m???2. The seed protein content of chickpea was found to be significantly reduced above a weed density of 25 plants m???2. Maximum N, P and K uptake by dragon spurge was 1,520, 1,020, and 7,350 mg m???2, respectively. Thus, dragon spurge should be controlled at densities above 5 plants m???2 to achieve optimum chickpea yield. Nomenclature: Chickpea, Cicer arietinum L.; Euphorbia dracunculoides Lam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of resistant source in lentil germplasm against Fusarium wilt in relation to environmental factors</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_fatima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_fatima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lentil is a valuable human food and one of the oldest known protein rich food legumes which is also known as poor men&amp;rsquo;s meat. Owing to biotic and abiotic stresses, the crop yield is below attainable levels which are mainly attributed to pathological factors especially lentil wilt caused by Fusarium oxysporum f.sp. lentis. It is a potential threat to lentil production not only in Pakistan but worldwide as well that can cause complete crop failure. Current studies were designed to screen the available lentil germplasm against the lentil wilt disease in relation to environmental factors. Twenty eight lentil lines were sown in a previously developed wilt sick bed in the research area of Pulses Research institute, Faisalabad using augmented design. Natural inoculum was also relied upon. Disease severity data were
recorded and area under disease progress curve was calculated. Results revealed that sixteen lines were found highly susceptible, seven remained susceptible, and three lines were moderately resistant whereas two demonstrated resistance responses against the disease. Furthermore, disease severity data along with weekly environmental conditions were subjected to correlation and stepwise regression analysis to screen environmental variables not having a significant influence on lentil wilt development. All the environmental factors were positively correlated with disease development and best explained using linear regression. Maximum disease severity was recorded at 17-18 o C and 7-10 o C air temperature (Max. and Min.), 60-78% relative humidity and 2 mm rainfall respectively. Stepwise regression employed to predict lentil wilt incidence, the model developed significantly fit to the data and their predicted values of lentil wilt incidence were in close conformity with the observed values.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMMI Biplot analysis for comparative evaluation of maize genotypes under different saline environments</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_aslam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_aslam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Salinity is amongst the leading abiotic stresses which adversely affects the  crop productivity. It brings multiple disorders in normal plant functionality and 
suppresses yield up to drastic level. Under subjection to salinity, maize crop interacts differently with different environmental conditions and shows different responses. Plants interact positively, negatively and sometimes no interaction with environment for various plant traits. Genotype x Environment Interaction (GEI) of maize genotypes with three salinity levels was studied for some selected morpho-physiological traits i.e. root shoot ratio, cholorphyll a, cholorphyll b, B-carotenoids, 
ascorbic acid, root density and leaf temperature using AMMI biplot analysis. OH41, OH28, OH8, USSR40 and WM13RA for root shoot ratio (RSR) and A556 for B-carotenoids (BCart) were proved stable genotypes whereas; all other genotype interacted with stressed conditions either positively or negatively. Ascorbic acid and B-carotenoid contents were proved good indicators of salt tolerance
in maize plant. AMMI biplot analysis proved to be an effective technique for study of GEI. Stable genotypes can be regarded for further breeding program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mulching Improves Water Productivity, Yield and Quality of Fine Rice under Water-saving Rice Production Systems</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_jabran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2015_jabran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Water-saving rice production systems are inevitable in the wake of severe water shortage in rice-growing regions of the world. Mulches can improve water productivity, yield and quality of rice through increase in water retention. Studies were conducted for two consecutive years to assess the potential role of mulches (plastic and straw) in improving the performance of water-saving rice production systems in comparison with no mulch used and conventionally irrigated transplanted rice. Water-saving rice production systems in this study comprise aerobic rice and transplanted rice with intermittent irrigation. These systems saved water (18-27 %) with improved water productivity more than the conventional system. However, these systems caused a yield penalty of 22-37 %; nevertheless, these yield losses were compensated with the application of mulches under water-saving rice production systems. Both plastic and straw mulches were helpful in improving moisture retention and water productivity (0.18-0.25 kg grain m???3 water) relative to non-mulch treatments (0.19-0.29 kg grain m???3 water). Mulch application was also helpful in reducing the number of non-productive tillers and sterile spikelets, and improving the productive tillers, kernel number and size, and kernel quality. Plastic mulch was more effective than straw mulch in improving water retention, water productivity and reducing spikelet sterility. In conclusion, the mulching improved the soil moisture retention, and thus enhanced the rice water productivity, spikelet fertility, paddy yield and quality of rice. This signifies the importance of mulching in water-saving rice production systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bt transgenes minimally influence maize grain yield and lodging across plant populations</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_novacek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_novacek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adoption of maize (Zea mays L) hybrids containing Bt (Bacillus thuringiensis) transgenes and increased plant population is widespread but little scientific research exists on their interactions with production environments in the Western Maize Belt of the United States. Two pairs of near-isogenic Bt and non-Bt maize hybrids were grown under rainfed and irrigated conditions from 2008 to 2010 at target populations from 49,300 to 111,100 plants ha-1 near Mead, NE. The objective was to determine the influence of the presence/absence of Bt transgenes for European corn borer [Ostrinia nubilalis (H¸bner) - ECB] and corn rootworm [Diabrotica spp. - CRW] on maize yield and lodging across a range of target populations. Bt maize hybrids produced 0.6 Mg ha-1 more grain, 0.2 more ears m-2, and 1.3 g heavier 100-kernel weight than non-Bt hybrids in absence of visible ECB and CRW rootworm pressure. Yield of Bt and non-Bt hybrids responded similarly to increasing target population, with Dekalb DKC 58-16 and 58-19 increasing from 11.0 to 13.1 Mg ha-1 and Dekalb DKC 61-69 and 61-72 from 11.8 to 12.7 Mg ha-1 as the target population increased from 49,300 to 111,100 plants ha-1. Lodging increased linearly with increasing target population, with a greater increase in rainfed than irrigated environments. Lodging of Bt and non-Bt maize hybrids was inconsistent. Grain yield, seed and insecticide cost, likelihood of ECB and CRW infestation, and environmental concerns related to soil insecticide use should be the drivers when determining if Bt maize hybrid use is justified. If CRW resistance occurs, planting non-Bt maize hybrids along with application of soil insecticide is a viable alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Survival Rates of Cardiovascular Patients in Faisalabad</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cardiovascular diseases have become common problem in developing countries including Pakistan. Survival analysis is a statistical technique used to model the time duration to until one or more events happen, such as death in biological organisms and failure in mechanical systems. In this study, we modeled the survival rates of cardiovascular patients who had heart attacks using survival analysis and log-rank test was used to compare the survival rates across gender. It was observed that the survival rates were not the same across gender. Male patients had less chances of survival as compared to female patients. The data have been collected from cardiology center, District Headquarter (DHQ) Hospital, Faisalabad included 106 cardiovascular patients who had heart attacks were observed to check survival rate from which 60 were males and 46 were females.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Analysis of Hepatitis C Epidemiology in Faisalabad District</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_spatial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis C, caused by the Hepatitis C virus (HCV), is an infectious disease affecting mostly the liver. The infection is often without symptoms. However, long lasting infection can lead to scarring of the liver. HCV is spreading mostly by blood-to-blood contact, drug use, poorly sterilized medical equipment and transfusions. The disease is becoming a major health problem for developing countries including Pakistan. World Health Organization rated Pakistan as second country in the world having high rates of chronic liver infections. About 8.6 million Pakistanis are affected with Hepatitis C. Spatial epidemiology is a discipline to understand the relationship between disease risk and exposures of interest. In this study the incidence data on Hepatitis C collected from the Allied Hospital Faisalabad over the period 2010-2012 were analyzed and the spatial dependency of the Hepatitis C risk was explored using spatial statistics besides risks were used to create surface maps of Faisalabad over the period 2010-2012 to identify areas at high risk in the Faisalabad city. It has been found that more than half of the rural population of Faisalabad city is suffering from Hepatitis C.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential use of GGE Bi-plot analysis to evaluate white Sorghum grain attributes for end uses</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_yaseen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2014_yaseen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genotype (G) and environment (E) interaction effects for grain quality are important to processors of white sorghum grain. The objective of this study was to analyze the genotype plus genotype-by-environment interaction effect (GGE) for grain attributes of 11white-grained sorghum G produced in 12 E in Nebraska. Environments included combinations of 4 locations, and two years, water regimes and N levels. GGE analysis can help processors of sorghum grain by selection of G and E to meet kernel mass, starch concentration and viscosity desired for different uses since GGE accounted for 18 to 23% of total variation, but not for yield and hardness since GGE accounted for &amp;lt; 5% of total variation. Heavy kernel mass sorghum grain would be best using Pioneer 84Y00 or Dekalb DK41-44 produced at Mead. Fontanelle W-1000, Kelly Green Seeds KG6902 and Asgrow Eclipse would produce high starch concentrations in environments with adequate N supply. Macia produced high peak and soft final viscosities, and high peak temperatures. Asgrow Eclipse produced low peak and hard final viscosities, while NC+7W92 produced low peak time and pasting temperatures. Pioneer 84Y00was more stable than the other genotypes for kernel mass, high peak viscosity and final viscosity, while Asgrow Eclipse was more stable for low peak viscosity and peak time. GGE analysis can help processors in selection of the best production areas and genotypes for different end uses of sorghum grain, but is limited by the ability to characterize and control environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food-handling Practices and Knowledge among Families with Young Children</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_lum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_lum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Children are at higher risk for foodborne illness than adults. Primary food handlers for young children have a direct impact on their child&amp;rsquo;s food safety risk. The objective of this study was to determine food safety handling practices and knowledge of main food preparers in families with children &amp;lt; 10 years of age. Participants (n = 503) were female (67%), Caucasian (80%), 30-49 years of age (83%), college educated (79%) and had one to two children 10 years and younger (83%). Responses were compared to Healthy People 2020 objectives/goals for food safety. The number of safe food-handling practices always practiced that met the goals were categorized by concept: Clean; 2, Separate; 1, Cook; 3, Chill; 4. Average food safety knowledge scores exceeded the Healthy People 2020 goals for Clean, 85%, 5.1 ± 1.1 (6-point scale) and Cook, 80%, 8.0 ± 2.9 (10-point scale) but not for Separate, 69%, 8.3 ± 1.9 (12-point scale) or Chill, 78%, 10.9 ± 1.9 (14-point scale). The lower knowledge scores for the Separate and Chill concepts indicate that food safety educators should focus on these concepts when designing messages for this population.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural, mechanical and chemical weed control in wheat</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_jabran/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_jabran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Effective weed control in wheat crop promises attractive grains harvest and subsequent food security in Pakistan. The objective of this study was to evaluate cultural (stale seed bed and double seed rate), mechanical (bar harrow, hand hoeing and hand pulling) and chemical weed control (bromoxynil+MCPA, fenoxaprop-p-ethyl, and a combination of both] for managing weeds and improving yield in wheat crop. Weed control methods varied in suppressing weeds and improving grain yield of wheat. A combined spray of bromoxynil+MCPA and fenoxaprop-p-ethyl (450 + 937.5 g a.i. ha-1, respectively) was the most effective treatment in suppressing weeds and increasing wheat yield followed by the application of fenoxaprop-p-ethyl (937.5 g a.i. ha-1). Plant height, spike length and grains per spike were not affected by the weed control treatments. Productive tillers were
recorded maximum in double seed rate treatment due to higher seed rate. Cultural control (stale seed bed and double seed rate) possessed more than 60% decrease in weeds proliferation and subsequent 24% increase in grain yield over control. Mechanical weed control (bar harrow, hand hoeing and hand pulling) had reduced weeds biomass by 64-72% and increased grain yield over 29%. Chemical weed control was most effective in suppressing weeds, hence presenting a 70.2-87.6 reduction in total weeds density and 45.4-57.9 increase in grain yield over control. In conclusion, albeit the chemical weed control was most effective in suppressing weeds and improving yield, yet the cultural and mechanical weed control also offered rational weed suppression and yield improvement
and can be opted where the herbicides are in short supply or under the organic farming systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yield and Yield Components of Wheat (Triticum Aestivum L.) affected by Aphid feeding and sowing time at Multan, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_shahzad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_shahzad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We assessed feeding effect of Schizaphis graminum Rond. and Rhopalosiphum padi L. (Homoptera: Aphididae) on yield losses to wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) (Cv. Sahar) sown on November 05th (early November), November 20th (late November) and December 05th (early December) during 2011, at Multan, Punjab (Pakistan). Aphids were controlled by applying imidacloprid 200 SL with Knapsack sprayer, as one spray (5th March), two sprays (5th and 26th March 2012) and no spray (control). Aphid densities were recorded on weekly basis starting from 12th March. At harvest shoot biomass, number of grains per spike, thousand grain weight and yield were recorded. Polynomial orthogonal contrasts were employed for evaluation of sowing dates, insecticides and their interactions for spray treatments on yield and yield components. Aphid (S. graminum) was dominant over R. padi and its highest number was observed on March 26th, 2012 in all sowing dates of both species. Delayed sowing of wheat increased aphid abundance, however, application of imidacloprid significantly reduced it. Sowing dates and insecticide(s) significantly affected shoot biomass and number of grains/spike. Highly significant differences for thousand grain weight and yield were observed in all sowing dates. Early sowing and application of insecticide(s) significantly increased the yield of wheat. One spray and two sprays of imidacloprid could significantly increase 1000 grain weight and yield in late November and December sown wheat. From this investigation, it is evident that early sowing of wheat is the best for reducing the risk of aphid attack on wheat crop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Fertility Patterns of Pakistan during 1984-2007</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_zakria/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_zakria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modelling fertility patterns of a population has gained popularity among the demographers in recent years. This article investigates the fertility patterns of Pakistan
and its urban and rural regions. The analysis of age specific fertility rates (ASFRs) has demonstrated high fertility in rural population as compared to urban and overall Pakistan population during the period 1984-2007. Substantial respective decreases of 44.98%, 48.72% and 46.76% in total fertility rates (TFRs) of rural, urban and overall Pakistan have been observed during the past 23 years. Two parametric models, viz., Hadwiger function (Hadwiger, 1940) and Peristera and Kostaki model (Peristera and Kostaki, 2007) were used to model the ASFRs of rural, urban and overall Pakistan during the year 2007. The models used in this study have canonical demographic interpretation whereas the previous endeavors used to analyze the ASFRs of Pakistan were lacking this important aspect (Nasir et al., 2009). Using model selection criteria (Montgomery et al., 2012), the
Peristera and Kostaki model (Peristera and Kostaki, 2007) was found parsimonious to model the ASFRs of Pakistan where the estimated coefficients have practical demographic interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twin Rows Minimally Impact Irrigated Maize Yield, Morphology, and Lodging</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_novacek/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_novacek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twin rows are being promoted as a means to increase maize yield through increased interception of photosynthetically active radiation (PAR) and plant morphology modifi cation. Th e objective of this research was to explore the interactive eff ects of maize hybrid, plant population, and row confi guration on grain yield and grain yield components, interception of PAR during vegetative growth, plant morphology, and percent lodging. Twin-row irrigated maize produced the same grain yield as single-row production. Small changes in plant morphology and grain yield components and 2.3 to 4.2% increased interception of PAR at the V9 (nine leaves with visible collars) stage were documented for twin rows, but the sum of these did not result in changes in grain yield. Twin-row production increased lodging by 3.5%. Few interactions between row confi guration and hybrid and target population were found, leading to the conclusion that twin-row production of maize aff ords little opportunity to increase maize grain yields. Hybrid and plant population had a much larger eff ect on grain yield and lodging. Increasing the maize target population to 93,000 plants ha -1 maximized grain yield at 14.3 Mg ha -1 , and led to small changes in plant morphology that increased lodging from 6.8 to 14.9%. Ear height had the highest direct eff ect on lodging in both the low (2009) and high (2010) percent lodging years. Based on these results, current promotion of twin rows is not justifi ed for irrigated maize production in the western Maize Belt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the Age Specific Fertility Rates of Rural and Urban Areas of Pakistan During 1984-2007</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_modelingage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_modelingage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper investigates the fertility pattern of Pakistan and its major breakdown rural and urban areas. The analysis of the age specific fertility rates (ASFRs) illustrated the greater fertility in the rural population as compared to the urban and of Pakistan population during the period 1984-2007. Approximately, 44.98% decrease in total fertility rate (TFR) of urban population during the past 23 years has been seen whereas 48.72% and 46.76% decrease in TFR of urban area and of Pakistan respectively with reference to the 1984. Different parametric models were fitted on the ASFRs of rural, urban and Pakistan during the year 2007. But for the sake of comparison, the outcomes of only two highly significant parametric models i.e. Hadwiger function and Peristera and Kostaki model (P-K model-I) were discussed thoroughly in this paper. Consequently, the P-K model-I is proposed as a parsimonious model. To examine the disparity among the ASFRs of rural, urban and Pakistan, Gini coefficients &amp;amp; Lorenz curves were also computed for Pakistan as well as its major geographical regions. The Lorenz curves explained more concentration within the urban population as compared to the Pakistan and its rural population during 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of Optimum Field Plot Size and Shape in Paddy Yield Trial</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_masood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_masood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study was designed to estimate the optimum
plot size with the shape for field research experiments on paddy yield trial considering the effect of plot size on variability in yield of crop as well as studying the coefficients of variation of different plot sizes and shapes of plots. The Smith&amp;rsquo;s index of soil heterogeneity was computed to estimate optimum plot size and shape using yield data of the 12m◊24m recorded separately from each basic unit of 1m◊1m (288 basic units). Soil productivity contour map described graphically the productivity level of the experimental site. The index of soil heterogeneity (b = 0.491) indicated a degree of low similarity among the experimental plots. Variance per unit area and coefficient of variation decreased rapidly with an increase in the plot size. Based on the coefficient of variation the optimum plot size for paddy yield trial was estimated to be 6m◊12m with rectangle shape for Rice Research Institute, Kala Shah Kaku, Lahore. This estimated plot size is larger than the plot size of 3m◊5m generally used for paddy yield in the study area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural dentists Does growing up in a small community matter?</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_mcfarland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_mcfarland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background.&lt;/strong&gt; The aging of the dental work- force has implications for both patients and dentists, especially those in rural and underserved areas.Anecdotal information regarding dental workforce trends indicates that students from rural communities are more likely to practice in rural communities than are students from urban areas.Although the medical literature supports this premise relative to physicians, there are no data to verify this statement relative to dentistry. Therefore, the authors decided to study whether this premise applies to dentistry.
&lt;strong&gt;Methods.&lt;/strong&gt; The authors conducted a retrospective analysis of dental student records from a Midwestern dental school for the years 1980 through 2010 to determine if there was a statistical correlation between the size of a dental student&amp;rsquo;s town of origin and the size of the community where he or she practiced after graduation. They also examined what role, if any, the student&amp;rsquo;s sex played.
&lt;strong&gt;Results.&lt;/strong&gt; Dentists from rural areas were approximately six times more likely to practice in a rural area than were dentists from urban areas. Female dentists were only slightly less likely to practice in a rural community than were male dentists.
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion.&lt;/strong&gt; Dentists from rural communities were more likely to practice in rural communities than were dental students from urban areas.
&lt;strong&gt;Practice Implications.&lt;/strong&gt; To ensure future access to care in rural communities, rural dentists may want to recruit actively or work closely with dental students from rural areas when hiring associates or seeking purchasers for their dental practices.
&lt;strong&gt;Key Words.&lt;/strong&gt; Dentists; rural health; women dentists; private practice; retirement; students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to Dental Care for Rural Children: A Survey of Nebraska General Dentists</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2011_mcfarland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2011_mcfarland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt; Pediatric dentists are too few in number to care for all children. Therefore, the level of pediatric dental services provided by general dentists,
especially in rural areas, is crucial to improving the dental health of children.
&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; The objectives of the study were to establish a baseline in regard to the quantity of pediatric dental care provided by general dentists in rural Nebraska as well as to measure their interest, if any, in receiving additional pediatric training.
&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; All rural general dentists (n = 350) in the state of Nebraska received an Institutional Review Board (IRB) approved 12-item questionnaire. The response rate was 71% (n = 248). Both descriptive and bivariate analyses were conducted, including chi-square and the analysis of variance (ANOVA).
&lt;strong&gt;Findings:&lt;/strong&gt; Forty-five percent of rural Nebraska dentists devote more than 20% of their practice to serving the dental needs of children. One-third of all rural Nebraska dentists indicated they would like additional training in pediatric dentistry.
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt; A significant opportunity exists to provide additional pediatric training for general dentists in rural Nebraska to further increase access to care for children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment and Hybrid Influences on Rapid-Visco-Analysis Flour Properties of Food-Grade Grain Sorghum?</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2011_griess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2011_griess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grain processors would benefi t from information about the production environment and the infl uences of the sorghum [Sorghum bicolor (L.) Moench] hybrid on food-grade fl our properties. The objective of this study was to determine the effects of environment and hybrid on rapid-visco-analysis (RVA) fl our properties of commercially available food-grade sorghum. A randomized complete block experiment was planted in 12 environments, which included the 2004 and 2005 growing seasons and irrigated and dryland water regimes in eastern, central, and west central Nebraska, and a dryland, low-N environment in eastern Nebraska. The environment accounted for 71-85% of the total variation in RVA parameters, while the hybrid accounted for 11-23% and the environmentby- hybrid interaction, 1-3%. Unfortunately, the results of this experiment suggest that it is diffi cult to predict the effect that environment will have on resulting sorghum-fl our parameters. Although of secondary importance in terms of total variation in sorghum-fl our RVA properties, the choice of hybrid predictably and signifi - cantly contributes to sorghum-starch viscosity properties. Food-grade hybrids were grouped based on viscosity properties into those best suited for dry-mill and alkaline-cooked products (Asgrow Orbit; Sorghum Partners NK1486) and those best suited for porridge, consumable alcohol, and ethanol production (Kelly Green Seeds KG6902; NC+ Hybrids 7W92; Asgrow Eclipse; and Fontanelle W-1000). These results were consistent with those previously reported for grain density.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying the impact of farm mechanization on wheat production in Punjab-Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2011_yamin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2011_yamin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contribution of mechanical inputs in farming is considered in terms of farm mechanization. Farm mechanization has helped in increasing the cultivated area and yield of major crops like wheat, rice and maize to 0.4%, 10.4% and 27.3% respectively by bringing barren land under cultivation (GOP, 2006). To study the present status of farm mechanization in all the districts of Punjab using GIS, data of farm machines, sowing area and wheat crop production was collected from Census Organizations for 1994-95 to 2004-05. Graduated color maps and multivariate maps were used to analyze the spatial variation in farm mechanization in thirty four districts of Punjab upto year 2004. To analyze the combined effect of most common farm machines (tractors, disc plows, cultivators, tubewells and threshers) on cultivated area of wheat and its production, multivariate maps help by considering the sum attribute of these farm machines. According to maps generated; Central, Southern and Eastern Punjab have greater area under cultivation as compared to Northern Punjab except Attock and Mianwali and there is a great need of recommended farm machines which may help to increase the wheat production for the same area under cultivation. Tractor horse power has a greater contribution in increasing cultivated area and the wheat production in 1994-1995 and 2004-05 but in some districts like D.G. Khan, Layyah and Muzaffar Garh, the wheat production can be increased by improving the impact of tractor horse power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Dentists of the Future: Dental School Enrollment Strategies</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_mcfarland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_mcfarland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study was to determine the relationship, if any, of a dental student&amp;rsquo;s 1) state of residency and 2) gender to his or her practice location in a rural Nebraska community after graduation. Previous research has demonstrated that dental students generally locate their practices near their place of rearing and that male graduates are more likely than female graduates to locate in rural areas. Dental student data for all University of Nebraska Medical Center College of Dentistry graduates from 1989 to 2008 (n=879) were analyzed. Descriptive and quantitative analyses were performed utilizing SPSS software (version 17.0). Chi-square and odds ratio analyses were also conducted. In contrast to previous research, women dentists who remained in the state after graduation were more likely to locate their practice in a rural community than were male dentists: 59 percent and 48.5 percent, respectively. Nonresidents who remained in the state after graduation were also more likely to locate in a rural community than were residents: 69 percent and 51 percent, respectively. Dental schools may find this information useful as state officials and policymakers look to dental schools for leadership in addressing dental workforce needs, especially in rural/underserved areas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment and Hybrid Influences on Food-Grade Sorghum Grain Yield and Hardness</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_griess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_griess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few studies have examined grain quality of food-grade sorghum hybrids. The objective of this study was to determine the effects of environment and hybrid on grain quality of commercially available food-grade sorghums. A
randomized complete block experiment with three replications was planted in 12 environments, which included the 2004 and 2005 growing seasons and irrigated and dryland water regimes in eastern, central, and west central Nebraska and a dryland low-N environment in
eastern Nebraska. Environment accounted for 5 to 140 times greater variation in measured parameters than hybrid, and the hybrid X environment interaction accounted for less than 2% of the total variation. Grain yield and kernel mass varied, with low yields of 1.4 Mg ha -1 and kernels weighing 9.5 g 1000 kernels -1 in the low-N 2004 environment, high grain yields of 10.5 Mg ha -1 under irrigated conditions in central Nebraska in
2005, and kernels weighing 27.8 g 1000 kernels -1
in the eastern Nebraska dryland 2005 environment. Harder grain was produced in 2005 than in 2004, with the west central and central 2005 environments having the lowest tangential abrasive dehulling device (TADD) removals of
14%. Non-food-grade hybrids produced higher grain yields and kernel mass than food-grade hybrids. Grain hardness was greater for non-food-grade and medium maturity hybrids when environmental means were lower (i.e., softer) but showed little or no difference in hardness when environmental means were high. Nebraska production environments have the capability to produce high quality food-grade sorghums for specific food uses to benefit both the producer and the food processor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of three Pakistani sheep breeds for their natural resistance to artificial infection of Haemonchus contortus.</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_saddiqi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_saddiqi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study was carried out to evaluate three Pakistani sheep breeds (Kachhi, Lohi and Thalli) for their natural resistance against artificial infection of Haemonchus contortus. Lambs were weaned at 3 months of age, housed in separate pens and treated with Avermectin to eliminate gastrointestinal nematode infection. Each lamb was infected orally with approximately 10,000 third stage larvae of H. contortus. Selected breeds were compared on the basis of parasitological, haematological, biochemical and histopathological parameters over a period of 9 weeks. Faecal egg counts were measured weekly while packed cell volume, total serum protein, serum albumin and live weight were determined fortnightly. At 9th-week post-infection, 10 animals of each breed were randomly selected and slaughtered for worm, eosinophil and mast cell counts from the abomasum of each animal. Faecal egg counts and worm burden were significantly lower (P &amp;lt; 0.05) in Lohi sheep than Kachhi and Thalli breeds. Furthermore, the Lohi breed also exhibited the highest levels of packed cell volume, total serum protein, albumin as well as eosinophils and mast cell counts. Breed ◊ week interaction also remained significant (P &amp;lt; 0.05) in most of the parameters for Lohi breed. The results suggested that Lohi breed expressed a significant innate resistance to artificial infection of H. contortus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple anthelmintic resistance and the possible contributory factors in Beetal goats in an irrigated area (Pakistan)</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2009_saeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2009_saeed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper presents the first report of multiple anthelmintic resistance in the gastrointestinal nematodes of goats and its possible contributory factors in an irrigated area (Pakistan). A total of 18 privately owned Beetal goat flocks were selected in order to determine the anthelmintic resistance against commonly used anthelmintics. Forty to 48 animals from each flock were selected according to their weight and egg count. The three anthelmintics viz., oxfendazole, levamisole and ivermectin, were given to three groups at manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s recommended dose while one group was kept as untreated control. Anthelmintic resistance was determined through faecal egg count reduction and egg hatch tests while assessment of the contributory factors of anthelmintic resistance was measured through the rural participatory approach. Faecal egg count reduction test revealed high prevalence of anthelmintic resistance (83.3%) and it was either single (levamisole) or multiple (oxfendazole and levamisole). Egg hatch test confirmed the resistance against oxfendazole as detected with faecal egg count reduction test. None of the goat flocks was resistant to ivermectin. Copro-cultures revealed that Haemonchus contortus, Trichostrongylus colubriformis and Teladorsagia circumcincta were the most common species exhibiting resistance to levamisole and oxfendazole. Step-wise logistic regression of the data on worm control practices revealed significant role of under-dosing, low-protein diets, healthcare supervision by the traditional healers and mass treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farmers&#39; perceptions of insect pests and pest management practices in Bt cotton in the Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2009_arshad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2009_arshad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aim of this study was to (1) examine the factors involved in the adoption or non-adoption of Bt cotton, (2) identify sources of Bt cotton seed acquisition, and (3) evaluate farmers&amp;rsquo; knowledge and perception of insect pests incidence and management practices in Bt cotton in the Punjab, Pakistan. A total of 150 farmers growing Bt cotton expressing Cry1Ac protein were interviewed in the main cotton-growing districts of the Punjab province. The main reasons for farmers adopting Bt cotton were to: (1) reduce bollworm damage; (2) reduce pesticide requirements; (3) obtain higher yield and profit; and (4) reduce labour. Most farmers were not initially aware of Bt cotton&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness against cotton bollworms and then grew it on a trial basis. The main sources of Bt cotton seed were the local market and seed companies while many farmers used home-retained Bt cotton seed, much as they do with conventional cotton. Our survey showed that farmers were aware of the major insect pests of cotton and reported a low incidence of cotton bollworms (Helicoverpa armigera, Pectinophora gossypiella, Earias vitella and E. insulana) and a high incidence of armyworm (Spodoptera litura and S. exigua) and sucking pests (Bemisia tabaci, Thrips tabaci, Amrasca devastans and Aphis gossypii) in Bt cotton. Farmers also noted the incidence of a new pest, the cotton mealybug (Phenacoccus sp.), which caused major damage to the crop in most cotton-growing areas. Farmers knew little about natural enemies and diseases in their fields, but reported a high incidence of cotton leaf curl virus. Farmers still relied heavily on chemicals to control the pests in Bt cotton as they are easily persuaded by the advertisements of pesticide companies. To further understand farmers&amp;rsquo; perceptions of Bt cotton, a survey of 75 farmers not cultivating Bt cotton was conducted. The main reason for the rejection of Bt cotton by farmers was that they were not sure of its effectiveness against insect pests. Higher prices of Bt cotton seed, perception of higher vulnerability to viral infection and greater requirements for fertilisers and irrigation were also reasons for rejection of Bt cotton cultivation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative productive performance and egg characteristics of pullets and spent layers</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2008_yasmeen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2008_yasmeen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Production performance and egg quality characteristics of pullets and spent layers were compared in this study. Forty birds, each from the flocks of pullets (24 weeks old) and spent layers (76 weeks old) were selected as experimental birds. The birds from each age group were divided into five replicates, each comprising of eight birds. All the experimental birds were fed a commercial layer ration @ 110g/bird/day for 12 weeks. The data on egg production, feed consumption, egg weight and egg quality characteristics viz. shell thickness, shell weight, breaking strength, albumen diameter, albumen weight and yolk weight were recorded. The data thus collected were utilized for calculation of FCR, Haugh unit and yolk index values. The results revealed that pullets produced more eggs and utilized their feed more efficiently than spent layers. However, egg weight in spent layers was higher than in their counterparts. Pullets also produced eggs with thicker shell and higher Haugh unit values when compared to the spent layers. Feed consumption and yolk index values remained unaffected due to the age. Pullets also had better egg quality characteristics than those of spent layers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal of Lead from Calcareous Contaminated Soils by Organic Acids</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2008_saifullah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2008_saifullah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The comparative performance of two organic acids (EDTA, citric acid) for the removal of Pb from two texturally different soils (loamy sand, sandy clay loam soil) was evaluated. The extraction of Pb increased with increasing organic acid concentration and removal from sandy clay soil was lower than from loamy sand soil. Maximum Pb removal (330.6 mg kg-1) was achieved in loamy sand soil where highest concentration (32 mmol kg-1) of EDTA was applied. However, in sandy clay loam soil, same rate of EDTA application had 1.4 times less Pb extraction (240.0 mg kg-1) than that of loamy sand soil. In the case of citric acid relatively poor performance was observed at all the rates of application except at 32 mmol kg-1. Calcium extraction efficiency for each soil was different and it was a function of the concentration of organic acids. At lower rates, comparing EDTA performance in different soils, lower application rates (0-16 mmol kg-1) resulted in higher extraction of Ca in loamy sand soil as compared to sandy clay loam soil. However at the highest rate (32 mmol kg-1), EDTA application resulted in more Ca extraction in sandy clay loam soil. In the case of CA treatments, both the soil responded differently and Ca extraction from soils varied with the concentration of organic acid i.e., increasing CA concentration from 2 to 32 mmol kg-1 resulted in increased removal of Ca from both the soils. Increasing concentration of CA from 2 to 32 mmol kg-1 increased Ca extraction from 206.6 to 731.0 mg kg-1 in loamy sand soils where as for sandy clay loam soil Ca extraction was increased from 92.6 to 747.0 mg kg-1.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinants influencing prevalence of louse infestations on layers of District Faisalabad (Pakistan)</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_nadeem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_nadeem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper describes the influence of some epidemiological determinants on the prevalence of louse infestation on layers in Faisalabad (Pakistan).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seventy layer farms were screened to determine the prevalence of louse infestation and its determinants including age of the bird, availability of space per bird and frequency of litter change. Prevalence of Lipeurus caponis was highest (53∑2%), followed by Menacanthus stramineus (22∑16%), Goniodes dissimilis (12∑37%) and Goniodes gallinae (12∑37%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Older birds (36 to 74 weeks of age) were found with a significantly higher prevalence of louse infestation than younger birds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Month-wise prevalence of louse infestation was higher during the summer months (from April to August) and at older age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Birds kept at floor area allowances ranging from 0∑43 to 0∑55???m2 were highly infested with lice as compared to those provided with a space of 0∑61???m2 or higher per bird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Litter change frequency after every 8 weeks resulted in a reduced chance of louse infestation as compared to less frequent litter changing practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was concluded from the study that the louse infestation is a menace for the poultry production industry in Pakistan and age, space per bird and litter change frequency are the influencing determinants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further research on the chemotherapeutic trials and resistance in poultry should be continued for an effective lice control program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthelmintic activity of Chenopodium album (L.) and Caesalpinia crista (L.) against trichostrongylid nematodes of sheep</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_jabbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_jabbar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aim of the study&lt;/strong&gt;
The present study was carried out to determine the anthelmintic activity of Caesalpinia crista (L.) (Fabaceae) seed kernel and Chenopodium album (L.) (Chenopodiaceae) whole plant in order to justify their traditional use in veterinary medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials and methods&lt;/strong&gt;
In vitro anthelmintic activity of crude aqueous methanolic extract (AME) of both the plants was determined using mature Haemonchus contortus and their eggs in adult motility assay and egg hatch test, respectively. In vivo anthelmintic activity was evaluated in sheep naturally infected with mixed species of gastrointestinal nematodes by administering crude powder (CP) and AME in increasing doses (1.0-3.0 g/kg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;
Both plants exhibited dose- and time-dependent anthelmintic effects by causing mortality of worms and inhibition of egg hatching. Caesalpinia crista (LC50 = 0.134 mg/mL) was found to be more potent than Chenopodium album (LC50 = 0.449 mg/mL) in egg hatch test. In vivo, maximum reduction in eggs per gram (EPG) of faeces was recorded as 93.9 and 82.2% with Caesalpinia crista and Chenopodium album AME at 3.0 g/kg on day 13 and 5 post-treatment, respectively. Levamisole (7.5 mg/kg), a standard anthelmintic agent, showed 95.1-95.6% reduction in EPG.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point prevalence of gastrointestinal helminthiasis in ruminants in southern Punjab, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_raza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_raza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study was carried out to determine the prevalence of gastrointestinal helminthiasis in ruminants in an irrigated area of lower Punjab (Pakistan). For this purpose, 100 faecal samples were collected from sheep, goats, cattle and buffaloes. Parasitological procedures including direct and indirect methods (sedimentation and floatation) and coproculture were used for the identification of helminths. The overall prevalence of helminthiasis was 51% in cattle, 47% in buffaloes, 62% in sheep and 52% in goats, with nematodes being the most common helminths. The prevalence of helminths was higher in young animals compared with adults in cattle (P &amp;lt; 0.0001), buffaloes (P &amp;lt; 0.0001), sheep (P &amp;lt; 0.059) and goats (P = 0.010). The prevalence of different species of helminths also varied in different age groups, with Toxocara vitulorum being higher in calves than adults both in cattle (P = 0.017) and buffaloes (P &amp;lt; 0.0001). Sex-wise prevalence of helminths was higher in males than females for buffaloes (P &amp;lt; 0.0001) and sheep (P = 0.014) in contrast to cattle and goats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpha-Adrenergic Blocker (Doxazosin): Role in Medical Management of Ureteric Stone</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_malik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_malik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Majority of uncomplicated distal ureteric stones can be managed conservatively by non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDS), hormones, calcium channel blockers, corticosteroids, and alpha-adrenoreceptor blocker drugs. Oedema and ureteral spasm are two important contributing factors causing retention of stone. Objective of this study was to assess the outcome of using (NSAIDS) and
alpha blockers in the conservative management of distal ureteric stones. Total number of patients in this prospective study was 120 and study period was 15 months. Patients were divided into two groups, A &amp;amp; B. Group A patients were managed by NSAIDS alone. Group B patients received NSAIDS along with alpha blocker doxazosin. Use of alpha blocker along with NSAIDS proved to be better than the use of NSAIDS alone. Stone expulsion rate was greater in group B. similarly duration of treatment, need for hospitalization, pain episodes, use of analgesics and surgical interventions were less in group B.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance of suflower in response to nitrogen management at different stages</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_munir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_munir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Studies were conductesd for two years (2004 and 2005) to access the comparative productivity of sunflower to nitrogen application in various splits. Nitrogen was applied at 100 Kg ha&amp;rsquo; as full at sowing, full at 1s t irrigation, full at flowering, Y 2 at sowing + Y 2 at 1st irrigation, Y 2 at sowing + Y 2 at flowering, Y 2 at 1 st irrigation + Y 2 at flowering, 1/3 at sowing + 1/3 at 1st irrigation + 1/3 at flowering, 1/3 at sowing + 1/3 at 1st irrigation + 1/3 at seed formation and 1/3 at sowing + 1/3 at flowering + 1/3 at seed formation. The highest achene yields of 2446 kg ha&amp;rsquo; and 2370 kg ha&amp;rsquo; were obtained in 2004 and 2005, respectively from plots, where nitrogen was applied in three equal splits at sowing, at first irrigation and at flowering. The mean crop growth rate (21.52 and 20.95 g m2 day&amp;rdquo;) and mean net assimilation rate (8.97 and 8.78 g m∑2 day&amp;rdquo;) also gave significantly highest values in the same treatment during both years. All the quality traits were significantly affected with the application of nitrogen in oil.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct and indirect anthelmintic effects of condensed tannins in sheep</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_iqbal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_iqbal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anthelmintic activity of condensed tannins (CT) was evaluated both in vitro and in vivo. In vitro tests included egg hatch test and paralysis/mortality assay on adult Haemonchus contortus. In vivo anthelmintic effect was determined by faecal egg count reduction test in lambs. To this end, 18 lambs were divided into three groups (low tannin, high tannin and control). The lambs of low and high tannin groups were fed diets containing 2 and 3% CT while the control group was fed on diets without CT. In vitro trials showed a dose-dependent inhibition of nematode egg hatching; whereas, there was no effect of CT on adult H. contortus. In vivo trials indicated reduction in faecal egg counts in lambs fed diets containing CT. Feed intake and nutrient digestibility of CT-fed sheep was lower and nitrogen balance was higher as compared to control. Maximum weight gain was observed in animals fed diets containing 3% CT. The direct anthelmintic effect of CT, therefore, was evidenced by inhibited egg hatching; whereas, faecal egg counts reduction in sheep was through improved nutrient utilization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and forecasting the sugarcane yield of Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2005_yaseen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2005_yaseen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study was planned to Model and forecast the sugarcane yield of Pakistan. The findings of present study are based on sugarcane yield data during the period (1947-2002). The most appropriate Model for the present study is ARIMA (2, 1, 2). Forecasting was also done up to 2008-2009. For comparison purposes, first three forecast values from 1999-2000 to 2001-2002 are compared with the actual values. Forecasts values are very close to the actual values.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
