<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haemonchus contortus on Muhammad Yaseen</title>
    <link>https://myaseen208.com/tags/haemonchus-contortus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Haemonchus contortus on Muhammad Yaseen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myaseen208.com/tags/haemonchus-contortus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of three Pakistani sheep breeds for their natural resistance to artificial infection of Haemonchus contortus.</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_saddiqi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2010_saddiqi/</guid>
      <description>This study was carried out to evaluate three Pakistani sheep breeds (Kachhi, Lohi and Thalli) for their natural resistance against artificial infection of Haemonchus contortus. Lambs were weaned at 3 months of age, housed in separate pens and treated with Avermectin to eliminate gastrointestinal nematode infection. Each lamb was infected orally with approximately 10,000 third stage larvae of H. contortus. Selected breeds were compared on the basis of parasitological, haematological, biochemical and histopathological parameters over a period of 9 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple anthelmintic resistance and the possible contributory factors in Beetal goats in an irrigated area (Pakistan)</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2009_saeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2009_saeed/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the first report of multiple anthelmintic resistance in the gastrointestinal nematodes of goats and its possible contributory factors in an irrigated area (Pakistan). A total of 18 privately owned Beetal goat flocks were selected in order to determine the anthelmintic resistance against commonly used anthelmintics. Forty to 48 animals from each flock were selected according to their weight and egg count. The three anthelmintics viz., oxfendazole, levamisole and ivermectin, were given to three groups at manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s recommended dose while one group was kept as untreated control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct and indirect anthelmintic effects of condensed tannins in sheep</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_iqbal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2007_iqbal/</guid>
      <description>Anthelmintic activity of condensed tannins (CT) was evaluated both in vitro and in vivo. In vitro tests included egg hatch test and paralysis/mortality assay on adult Haemonchus contortus. In vivo anthelmintic effect was determined by faecal egg count reduction test in lambs. To this end, 18 lambs were divided into three groups (low tannin, high tannin and control). The lambs of low and high tannin groups were fed diets containing 2 and 3% CT while the control group was fed on diets without CT.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>