<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muhammad Yaseen</title>
    <link>https://myaseen208.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Muhammad Yaseen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myaseen208.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contributions of Open Biomass Burning and Crop Straw Burning to Air Quality: Current Research Paradigm and Future Outlooks</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mehmood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2022_mehmood/</guid>
      <description>Since open biomass burning (OBB) and open crop straw burning (OCSB) could pose a great risk to human health via altering the air quality, these practices have grabbed considerable attention from the scientific community and policymakers in recent years. In order to have a greater and deeper understanding of the contributions of both OBB and OCSB on air quality, a bibliometric analysis was performed using the Web of Science core collection to understand the research developments and future perspectives of these issues between 1991 and 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global research on the air quality status in response to the electrification of vehicles</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_bao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_bao/</guid>
      <description>Electric vehicles (EVs) can substantially decrease atmospheric pollutant emissions, thereby improving air quality, decreasing global warming, and improving human health. In this study, we performed a comprehensive bibliometric analysis using Web of Science to understand the research developments and future perspectives in EVs between 1974 and 2021. The analysis of indicators such as research trends, publication growth, and keywords revealed that most research in the selected timeframe was focused on applying and optimizing the existing technologies of different types of EVs to decrease air pollution and mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Pensioners and their Time Use: A Case Study of District Rahimyar Khan, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</guid>
      <description>The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing. All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel parent selection strategy for the development of drought-tolerant cotton cultivars</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chattha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_chattha/</guid>
      <description>Drought is a devastating factor for crop production worldwide. Therefore, an experiment was conducted to study genetics for some agro-physiological traits in cotton under drought stress. The 13 parental cotton genotypes along with their 30 F1 hybrids were planted under normal and drought conditions. The mean performance of the genotypes was assessed through principal component and heat map analyses. The principal component analyses revealed 53.99 and 53.15% in the first two principal components of variability for normal and drought conditions, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Time Use of Nurses and Paramedical Staff, Working in Public Hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan, Bahawalpur, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</guid>
      <description>The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing. All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen application accelerates the downy mildew disease severity with leaf age in canola plants</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</guid>
      <description>Downy mildew is a devastating disease of canola. Two years study was conducted to find the impact of different nitrogen levels on disease severity of downy mildew with respect to leaf age on canola plants in field conditions. Three nitrogen levels (11.50???Kg acre???1, 23???Kg acre???1 and 34.5???Kg acre???1) were applied in soil when plants were 40???days old. In control, 0???Kg acre???1 N was applied. The diseased leaves from the lower, middle and upper part of the plant were tagged and data were recorded after 10?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The level of Cry1Ac endotoxin and its efficacy against H. armigera in Bt cotton at large scale in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</guid>
      <description>A biophysical survey was conducted in 15 cotton-growing districts of Pakistan. Four hundred cotton growers were approached and inquired about the production technology of Bt cotton. Further, 25 strip tests using combo strips (Cry1Ac, Cry2Ab, Vip3Aa and Cp4, EPSPS gene) were performed at each farmer&amp;rsquo;s field. Out of 10,000 total-tested samples, farmers claimed 9682 samples as Bt and 318 samples as non-Bt. After performing a strip test, 1009 and 87 samples were found false negative and false positive, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Fine and Coarse Rice Varieties for Nickel Accumulation and Growth Response at Different Levels of Nickel</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_fatma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_fatma/</guid>
      <description>The differential growth response and nickel (Ni) accumulation by two rice varieties grown in Ni-contaminated soil are investigated. Soil is contaminated with Ni at different levels viz. control (0), 7, 15, 22, 30, and 38 mg kg???1 soil. Two rice varieties viz. Basmati-2000 (fine variety) and KSK-133 (coarse variety) are grown in pots containing Ni-contaminated soil. The plants are harvested at four growth stages with an interval of 15 days. Harvested plants are washed with distilled water to remove aerial deposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Service Eight Weeks Mandatory Pre-Promotion Training Research Officer (BS-17) to Senior Research Officer (BS-18) 1st Session</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2021-01-29-fsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2021-01-29-fsa/</guid>
      <description>Workshop In-Service Eight Weeks Mandatory Pre-Promotion Training Research Officer (BS-17) to Senior Research Officer (BS-18) 1st Session held on January 19-20, 2021 &amp;amp; February 29, 2021 at Forest Services Academy Ghoragali, Murree, Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Service Eight Weeks Mandatory Pre-Promotion Training Research Officer (BS-17) to Senior Research Officer (BS-18) 1st Session</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2021-01-22-fsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2021-01-22-fsa/</guid>
      <description>Workshop In-Service Eight Weeks Mandatory Pre-Promotion Training Research Officer (BS-17) to Senior Research Officer (BS-18) 1st Session held on January 19-20, 2021 at Forest Services Academy Ghoragali, Murree, Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Service Eight Weeks Mandatory Pre-Promotion Training Research Officer (BS-17) to Senior Research Officer (BS-18) 1st Session</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2021-01-19-fsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2021-01-19-fsa/</guid>
      <description>Workshop In-Service Eight Weeks Mandatory Pre-Promotion Training Research Officer (BS-17) to Senior Research Officer (BS-18) 1st Session held on January 19-20, 2021 at Forest Services Academy Ghoragali, Murree, Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Course on Capacity Building of NARS Scientists in Advance Analytical Techniques</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2020-10-27-narc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2020-10-27-narc/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Training Course on Capacity Building of NARS Scientists in Advance Analytical Techniques held on October 27-29, 2020 at Ayub Agricultural Research Institute (AARI), Faisalabad , Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design &amp; Analysis of Field Experiments using R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2020-03-06-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2020-03-06-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Regression Analysis Simple Linear Regression Example Example Example  Multiple Linear Regression Example  Polynomial Regression Analysis Example  Analysis of Variance (ANOVA) Example Example  Analysis of Covariance (ANCOVA) Example Same intercepts but different slopes Different intercepts and different slopes  Correlation Analysis Simple Correlation Analysis Example  Partial Correlation Analysis Example  Multiple Correlation Analysis Example  Completely Randomized Design (CRD) Example  Randomized Complete Block Design (RCBD) Example  Latin Square Design Example  Factorial Experiment under RCBD Stability Analysis Individual Analysis of Variance for each Location Combined Analysis of Variance Additive Main Effects and Multiplicative Interaction (AMMI) Analysis Additive Main Effects and Multiplicative Interaction (AMMI) Biplot Analysis Genotype plus Genotypes by Environment (GGE) Interaction Biplot Analysis    Introduction  R is a free, open-source programming language and software environment for statistical computing, bioinformatics, visualization and general computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptability trials of sesame germplasm against macrophomina phaseolina (tassi) goid by using ammi biplot analysis in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_bashir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_bashir/</guid>
      <description>The current research was conducted to exploit the adaptability/resistance status of different sesame varieties/advanced lines of sesame germplasm against charcoal rot under different environmental conditions through AMMI Biplot analysis. Ten varieties/advanced lines of sesame viz., TS-5, 10003, 40009, 50009, 50011, 50022, 16001, 40004, Black Till and TH-6 were collected from Ayub Agricultural Research Institute (AARI), Faisalabad, Pakistan. The seeds of sesame varieties/advanced lines were sown at six different locations namely Faisalabad, Toba Tek Singh, Piplan, Bhakhar, Mandi Baha Uddin and Bahawalpur with three replications under Randomized Complete Block Design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the Effect of Water Deficit on Cotton Genotypes Using Agro-physiological and Biochemical Parameters</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_chattha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2020_chattha/</guid>
      <description>To investigate the water-deficit tolerance, 45 cotton genotypes were grown under normal irrigation and water-deficit conditions for 2 years. Genotype x treatment x year interaction was determined for seed cotton yield, number of bolls, boll weight, chlorophyll fluorescence, proline contents, and total soluble proteins. Apart from proline levels, all traits showed a reduction under water-deficit conditions. The mean percentage reduction in seed cotton yield due to water deficit conditions was 52.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Course on Capacity Building of NARS Scientists in Advance Analytical Techniques</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-r-narc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-r-narc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Regression Analysis Simple Linear Regression Example Example Example  Multiple Linear Regression Example  Polynomial Regression Analysis Example  Analysis of Variance (ANOVA) Example Example  Analysis of Covariance (ANCOVA) Example Same intercepts but different slopes Different intercepts and different slopes  Correlation Analysis Simple Correlation Analysis Example  Partial Correlation Analysis Example  Multiple Correlation Analysis Example  Completely Randomized Design (CRD) Example  Randomized Complete Block Design (RCBD) Example  Latin Square Design Example  Factorial Experiment under RCBD Stability Analysis Individual Analysis of Variance for each Location Combined Analysis of Variance Additive Main Effects and Multiplicative Interaction (AMMI) Analysis Additive Main Effects and Multiplicative Interaction (AMMI) Biplot Analysis Genotype plus Genotypes by Environment (GGE) Interaction Biplot Analysis    Introduction  R is a free, open-source programming language and software environment for statistical computing, bioinformatics, visualization and general computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Course on Capacity Building of NARS Scientists in Advance Analytical Techniques</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-11-25-narc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-11-25-narc/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Training Course on Capacity Building of NARS Scientists in Advance Analytical Techniques held on November 25-28, 2019 at National Agricultural Research Centre, Islamabad, Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Econometrics using STATA</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-07-29-nibaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-07-29-nibaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Econometrics using STATA held during July 29, 2019 to August 2, 2019 at National Institute of Banking &amp;amp; Finance (NIBAF), Karachi, Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to wirte a Research Paper and Hands on Training of SPSS - A Statistical Tool</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-04-18-uol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-04-18-uol/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionStatisticsVariableMeasurementMeasurement ScalesDescriptive StatisticsExampleBoxwhisker DiagramExampleRegression AnalysisSimple Linear RegressionExampleExerciseExerciseMultiple Linear RegressionExampleCorrelation AnalysisSimple Correlation AnalysisExamplePartial Correlation AnalysisExampleIntroductionStatisticsStatistics deals with uncertainty &amp;amp; variabilityStatistics turns data into informationData -&amp;gt; Information -&amp;gt; Knowledge -&amp;gt; WisdomStatistics is the interpretation of ScienceStatistics is the Art &amp;amp; Science of learning from dataalt text</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st International Workshop on Scholarly Writing and Publishing</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-03-18-scholarly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-03-18-scholarly/</guid>
      <description>Workshop 1st International Workshop on Scholarly Writing and Publishing held on March 18-21, 2019 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Model using Python</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-pythonlmbzu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-pythonlmbzu/</guid>
      <description>Python Basics Variables and Data Types Variable Assignment Calculations With Variables Types and Type Conversion  Logical Operators Comparison If-Else Function Help  Simple Linear Regression Multiple Linear Regression Polynomial Regression Regression with Dummy Variables Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 Regression with same slopes and different intercepts Regression with different slopes and different intercepts     Python Basics Variables and Data Types Variable Assignment x = 5 x # dir(x) 5  Calculations With Variables x + 2 # Sum of two variables 7 x - 2 # Subtraction of two variables 3 x*2 # Multiplication of two variables 10 x**2 # Exponentiation of a variable 25 x%2 # Remainder of a variable 1 x/float(2) # Division of a variable 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: Programming for Statistics</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-02-18-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2019-02-18-python/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Python: Programming for Statistics will be held on February 18, 2019 at the Department of Statistics, Bahauddin Zakariya University, Multan, Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Quality in Textile Industry using Six Sigma with R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-sixsigmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2019-sixsigmar/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors affecting C-section deliveries in Punjab</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_jabeen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2018_jabeen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics with R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-bioinfor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-bioinfor/</guid>
      <description>Statistics Variable Measurement Measurement Scales Nominal Data Example Example  Ordinal Data Example  Two Way Contingency Table Example Example  Count Data Example  Continuous Data Example Example   Measures of Centeral Tendency Measures of Dispersion Measures of Skewness Measures of Skewness   Statistics   Statistics is the science of uncertainty &amp;amp; variability Statistics turns data into information Data -&amp;gt; Information -&amp;gt; Knowledge -&amp;gt; Wisdom Data Driven Decisions (3Ds) Statistics is the interpretation of Science Statistics is the Art &amp;amp; Science of learning from data     Variable   Characteristic that may vary from individual to individual Height, Weight, CGPA etc     Measurement   Process of assigning numbers or labels to objects or states in accordance with logically accepted rules     Measurement Scales   Nominal Scale: Obersvations may be classified into mutually exclusive &amp;amp; exhaustive classes or categories Ordinal Scale: Obersvations may be ranked Interval Scale: Difference between obersvations is meaningful Ratio Scale: Ratio between obersvations is meaningful &amp;amp; true zero point    Nominal Data Example  The following data shows the gender of a sample of twenty students from the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression Analysis with Python</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-regpython/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-regpython/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Statistics Variable Measurement Measurement Scales Regression Analysis Simple Linear Regression Example  Multiple Linear Regression Example  Polynomial Regression Analysis Example    Introduction   In God we trust, all others must bring data. (W. Edwards Deming) In Data we trust, all others must bring data.     Statistics   Statistics is the science of uncertainty &amp;amp; variability Statistics turns data into information Data -&amp;gt; Information -&amp;gt; Knowledge -&amp;gt; Wisdom Data Driven Decisions (3Ds) Statistics is the interpretation of Science Statistics is the Art &amp;amp; Science of learning from data     Variable   Characteristic that may vary from individual to individual Height, Weight, CGPA etc     Measurement   Process of assigning numbers or labels to objects or states in accordance with logically accepted rules     Measurement Scales   Nominal Scale: Obersvations may be classified into mutually exclusive &amp;amp; exhaustive classes or categories Ordinal Scale: Obersvations may be ranked Interval Scale: Difference between obersvations is meaningful Ratio Scale: Ratio between obersvations is meaningful &amp;amp; true zero point     Regression Analysis   Quantifying dependency of a normal response on quantitative explanatory variable(s)     Figure 1: Population Regression Function    Simple Linear Regression   Quantifying dependency of a normal response on a quantitative explanatory variable    Example   Weekly Income ($) Weekly Expenditures ($)    80 70  100 65  120 90  140 95  160 110  180 115  200 120  220 140  240 155  260 150    Income = [80, 100, 120, 140, 160, 180, 200, 220, 240, 260] Expend = [70, 65, 90, 95, 110, 115, 120, 140, 155, 150] import pandas as pd df1 = pd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Statistics using SPSS</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-08-16-pastic-ntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-08-16-pastic-ntu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Statistics Variable Measurement Measurement Scales Descriptive Statistics Example Reference  Boxwhisker Diagram Example Reference  Scatter Plot Example Reference  Regression Analysis Simple Linear Regression Example Reference  Multiple Linear Regression Example Reference  Polynomial Regression Analysis Example Reference  Analysis of Variance (ANOVA) Example Reference Example Reference  Analysis of Covariance (ANCOVA) Example Reference Same Slopes but different Intercepts Different Intercepts and different Slopes  Factorial Experiments Example Reference    Introduction alt text</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Statistics using SPSS</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2018-08-16-pastic-ntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2018-08-16-pastic-ntu/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to Statistics using SPSS will be held on August 16-17, 2018 at National Textile University, Faisalabad, Pakistan
 All workshop material is avaiable here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Technologies in Research: Google Apps and SPSS</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-05-15-pastic-fsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-05-15-pastic-fsd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Statistics Variable Measurement Measurement Scales Descriptive Statistics Example  Boxwhisker Diagram Example  Regression Analysis Simple Linear Regression Example Exercise Exercise  Multiple Linear Regression Example  Polynomial Regression Analysis Example  Analysis of Variance (ANOVA) Example Exercise  Analysis of Covariance (ANCOVA) Example Same intercepts but different slopes Different intercepts and different slopes  Correlation Analysis Simple Correlation Analysis Example  Partial Correlation Analysis Example  Multiple Correlation Analysis Example  Completely Randomized Design (CRD) Example  Randomized Complete Block Design (RCBD) Example  Latin Square Design Example    Introduction alt text</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Technologies in Research: Google Apps and SPSS</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2018-pastic-fsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2018-pastic-fsd/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Emerging Technologies in Research: Google Apps and SPSS will be held on May 15-16, 2018 at Ayub Agriculture Research Institute, Faisalabad, Pakistan
 All workshop material is avaiable here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Analysis of Pakistan Population Census 2017</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-05-13_ppcspatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-05-13_ppcspatial/</guid>
      <description>The latest version of the ppcSpatial package for R is now on CRAN. It performs spatial analysis for exploration of Pakistan Population Census 2017 (http://www.pbscensus.gov.pk/). It uses data from R package PakPC2017.
 The Spatial map is
 and full view is here.
 A video showing some functionality of the package is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to R for Agricultural Research</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-r-aari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-r-aari/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Regression Analysis Simple Linear Regression Example Example Example  Multiple Linear Regression Example  Polynomial Regression Analysis Example  Analysis of Variance (ANOVA) Example Example  Analysis of Covariance (ANCOVA) Example Same intercepts but different slopes Different intercepts and different slopes  Correlation Analysis Simple Correlation Analysis Example  Partial Correlation Analysis Example  Multiple Correlation Analysis Example  Completely Randomized Design (CRD) Example  Randomized Complete Block Design (RCBD) Example  Latin Square Design Example    Introduction  R is a free, open-source programming language and software environment for statistical computing, bioinformatics, visualization and general computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to R for Agricultural Research</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2018-r-aari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2018-r-aari/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An introduction to R for Agricultural Research will be held on May 09-11, 2018 at Ayub Agriculture Research Institute, Faisalabad, Pakistan
 All workshop material is avaiable here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ppcSpatial: Spatial Analysis of Pakistan Population Census</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/ppcspatialblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/ppcspatialblog/</guid>
      <description>The latest version of the ppcSpatial package for R is now on CRAN. It performs spatial analysis for exploration of Pakistan Population Census 2017 (http://www.pbscensus.gov.pk/). It uses data from R package PakPC2017.
A video showing some functionality of the package is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VetResearchLMM v1.0.0 on CRAN</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/vetresearchlmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/vetresearchlmm/</guid>
      <description>The latest version of the VetResearchLMM package for R is now on CRAN. This package provides R Codes and Datasets for Duchateau, L. and Janssen, P. and Rowlands, G. J. (1998). Linear Mixed Models. An Introduction with applications in Veterinary Research. International Livestock Research Institute. The latest version of the package is prepare for new version of lmerTest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diallel Analysis with R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/diallelanalysisr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/diallelanalysisr/</guid>
      <description>The latest versin 0.1.1 of DiallelAnalysisR is aviable on CRAN. It performs Diallel Analysis with R using Griffing’s and Hayman’s approaches. Four different methods (1: Method-I (Parents + F1’s + reciprocals); 2: Method-II (Parents and one set of F1’s); 3: Method-III (One set of F1’s and reciprocals); 4: Method-IV (One set of F1’s only)) and two methods (1: Fixed Effects Model; 2: Random Effects Model) can be applied using Griffing’s approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 22:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/help/</guid>
      <description>This is not a help service for all your Statistics, R, Python and/or LaTeX questions, so please don&amp;rsquo;t post questions in the comments, or send them to me by email.
If you have questions about Statistics and/or data analysis, ask for help on crossvalidated.com.
If you have questions about R, ask for help on stackoverflow.com.
If you have questions about Python, ask for help on stackoverflow.com.
If you have questions about LaTeX, ask for help on stackoverflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About myaseen208</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 16:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/about/</guid>
      <description>This is my blog site where I will put my thoughts about Statistics, R, Python, LaTeX and Research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis with R: Introduction of R Language</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-r-maldives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/blogs/2018-r-maldives/</guid>
      <description>The Workspace Data types Vectors Matrices Lists Data Frames Reading/writing data from/to files (Import/Export Data) Connecting to the database Numerical or Graphical Summaries of data. Summarize Data Bar charts and Dot charts ggplot2 package  The mpg Data Frame Data Transformation Filter Rows with filter() Comparisons Logical Operators Missing Values Arrange Rows with arrange() Select Columns with select() Add New Variables with mutate() PakPC2017Tehsil Data Frame Scatter Plot dygraphs plotly datatable   The Workspace The workspace is your current R working environment and includes any user-defined objects (vectors, matrices, data frames, lists, functions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study of Different Amendments on Amelioration of Saline-Sodic Soils Irrigated with Water Having Different EC: SAR Ratios</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_murtaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_murtaza/</guid>
      <description>Soil degradation affects soil properties such as structure, water retention, porosity, electrical conductivity (EC), sodium adsorption ratio (SAR), and soil flora and fauna. This study was conducted to evaluate the response of contrasting textured soils irrigated with water having different EC:SAR ratios along with amendments: gypsum (G), farm manure (FM), and mulch (M). Water of different qualities viz. EC 0.6 + SAR 6, EC 1.0 + SAR 12, EC 2.0 + SAR 18, and EC 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Equation Modeling with Latent Variables using R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-comsats-lahore-sem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-comsats-lahore-sem/</guid>
      <description>Symposium Structural Equation Modeling with Latent Variables using R during Symposium on Professional Development of New Generation of Research Scholars held on December 14, 2017 at COMSATS Institute of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-nibaf-islamabad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-nibaf-islamabad/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Applied Econometrics during Statistical Officers Training Scheme (SOTS-7) held on December 12-13, 2017 at National Institute of Banking &amp;amp; Finance (NIBAF), Islamabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of training for in-hand manipulation on legibility of Urdu handwriting</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_jameel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_jameel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ffect of source of procurement of milk on the composition of milk supplied in Rawalpindi city</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ishaq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2017_ishaq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Methods for Researchers using R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r2-science-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r2-science-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Statistical Methods for Researchers using R held on August 10-12, 2017 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Methods for Researchers using R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r1-science-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r1-science-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Statistical Methods for Researchers using R held on August 07-09, 2017 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R &amp; Bioconductor for Computational Biology &amp; Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-bioconductor-nibge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-bioconductor-nibge/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to R &amp;amp; Bioconductor for Computational Biology &amp;amp; Bioinformatics during one day international workshop on Application of Computational Biology in Biotechnology held on July 31, 2017 at National Institute for Biotechnology and Genetic Engineering (NIBGE), Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to LaTeX: UAF Synopsis and Thesis</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-latex-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-latex-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to LaTeX: UAF Synopsis and Thesis held on July 26-28, 2017 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics for Veterinary and Animal Science using R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r2-vet-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r2-vet-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Statistics for Veterinary and Animal Science using R held on July 20-22, 2017 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics for Veterinary and Animal Science using R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r1-vet-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-r1-vet-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Statistics for Veterinary and Animal Science using R held on July 17-19, 2017 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Linear Mixed Modeling for Agricultural Sciences</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-glmm-bzu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-glmm-bzu/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Generalized Linear Mixed Modeling for Agricultural Sciences held on February 25, 2017 at Bahauddin Zaria University, Multan, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical and Patent Writing</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-technical-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2017-technical-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Technical and Patent Writing held on January 28, 2017 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-latex-iccs14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-latex-iccs14/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to LaTeX held on December 13, 2016 during 14-th Islamic Countries Conference on Statistical and Allied Sciences (ICCS-14) held on December 12-15, 2016 at Multan, Pakistan**</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Linear Mixed Models using R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-glmm-iccs14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-glmm-iccs14/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Generalized Linear Mixed Models using R held on December 13, 2016 during 14-th Islamic Countries Conference on Statistical and Allied Sciences (ICCS-14) held on December 12-15, 2016 at Multan, Pakistan**</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Potential of Multivariate Analysis to Study the Impact of Cotton Leaf Curl Disease on Yield Traits</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_raza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_raza/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reclamation of wastewater containing Cu(II) using alginated Mentha spicata biomass</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_ansari/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_ansari/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMMI Biplot analysis for comparative evaluation of maize genotypes under different saline environments</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_aslam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_aslam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis and Forecasting of Water Reservoir in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_batool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2016_batool/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Econometrics with R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-econr-sbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-econr-sbp/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to Econometrics with R held on February 22-25, 2016 at National Institute of Banking &amp;amp; Finance (NIBAF), State Bank of Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics: The Art and Science of Learning from Data</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-stat-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2016-stat-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Statistics: The Art and Science of Learning from Data held on February 6, 2016 at the University of Agriculture Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Techniques for Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-mcmc-nim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-mcmc-nim/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Quantitative Techniques for Decision Making during 20-th Mid-Career Management Course (MCMC) held on August 24-25, 2015 at National Institute of Management, Lahore, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-latex-sbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-latex-sbp/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to LaTeX held on May 27, 2015 at National Institute of Banking &amp;amp; Finance (NIBAF), State Bank of Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-r-sbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-r-sbp/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to R held on May 25-26, 2015 at National Institute of Banking &amp;amp; Finance (NIBAF), State Bank of Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Equation Modeling with R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-sem-iqra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-sem-iqra/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Structural Equation Modeling with R held on May 24, 2015 at Iqra University, Karachi, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Method of Moments Estimation with R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-gmm-iqra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-gmm-iqra/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Generalized Method of Moments Estimation with R held on April 06, 2015 at Iqra University, Karachi, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-r-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2015-r-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to R held on March 28, 2015 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2014-latex-sbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2014-latex-sbp/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to LaTeX held on August 13, 2014 at National Institute of Banking &amp;amp; Finance (NIBAF), State Bank of Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2014-r-sbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2014-r-sbp/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to R held on August 11-12, 2014 at National Institute of Banking &amp;amp; Finance (NIBAF), State Bank of Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R-Programming Language for Statistical Computing</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2013-r-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2013-r-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop An Introduction to R-Programming Language for Statistical Computing held on May 24 to June 14, 2013 (16 Contact Hours) at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical and Economic Analysis of Experimental Data using Statistical Software</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2012-doe-ari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2012-doe-ari/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Statistical and Economic Analysis of Experimental Data using Statistical Software held on December 17-21, 2012 at Agricultural Research Institute (ARI), Muzaffarabad, AJK, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPSS Training for Social Sciences</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2007-spss-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2007-spss-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop SPSS Training for Social Sciences held on August 13-20, 2007 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Analysis of Agricultural Research Experiments using STATISTICA/Minitab (Biological Sciences)</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2007-doe-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2007-doe-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Design and Analysis of Agricultural Research Experiments using STATISTICA/Minitab (Biological Sciences) held on August 06-11, 2007 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical and Economical Analysis of Field Experiments</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2007-doe-azre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2007-doe-azre/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Statistical and Economical Analysis of Field Experiments held on May 21-25, 2007 at AZRE, Quetta, Balochistan, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Econometric Techniques using EViews</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2006-eviews-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2006-eviews-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Advanced Econometric Techniques using EViews held on August 24-29, 2006 at the Department of Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics, University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Applied Multivariate Statistical Techniques Using Different Statistical Packages</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2006-multivariate-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2006-multivariate-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Workshop on Applied Multivariate Statistical Techniques Using Different Statistical Packages held on June 05-10, 2006 at the Department of Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics, University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STATISTICA Training Workshop of Biological Scientists</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-statistica-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-statistica-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop STATISTICA Training Workshop of Biological Scientists held on August 08-13, 2005 at the University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPSS Training Workshop of Social Scientists</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-spss-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-spss-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop SPSS Training Workshop of Social Scientists held on August 01-06, 2005 at the Department of Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics, University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Biometric Techniques for Agricultural Research in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-biometric-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-biometric-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Advanced Biometric Techniques for Agricultural Research in Pakistan held on June 20-25, 2005 at the Department of Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics, University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Course on Design and Analysis of Agricultural Field Experiments using STATISTICA</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-statistica-narc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2005-statistica-narc/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Training Course on Design and Analysis of Agricultural Field Experiments using STATISTICA held on Feb 21-25, 2005 at Social Sciences Institute, National Agriculture Research Center, Islamabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Methodology and Analytical Techniques</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2004-research-uaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/seminars/2004-research-uaf/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Research Methodology and Analytical Techniques held from June 21, 2004 to July 03, 2004 at the Department of Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics, University of Agriculture, Faisalabad, Pakistan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Profile &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CV Curriculum Vitae &amp;nbsp;  Emailmyaseen208 on GitHubGoogle ScholarTwitter Data Scientist with twenty-two years of teaching &amp;amp; research experience executing data driven decisions &amp;amp; solutions to increase efficiency &amp;amp; accuracy
  Experienced at developing statistical models, using predictive data modeling &amp;amp; analyzing data algorithms to deliver insights &amp;amp; implement action-oriented solutions to complex problems
  Proficient in developing R package/software for statistical analysis &amp;amp; machine learning</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software I&#39;ve written</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/software/</guid>
      <description>This page provides links to R &amp;amp; LaTeX packages I have (co)authored. The most recent versions of most packages are on github. Most R packages are also available on CRAN.
 R Packages/SoftwareagriTutorialagriTutorial : Tutorial Analysis of Some Agricultural Experiments [Website]
bayesammibayesammi : Bayesian Estimation of the Additive Main Effects and Multiplicative Interaction Model [Website]
 baystabilitybaystability : Bayesian Stability Analysis of Genotype by Environment Interaction (GEI) [Website]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Winter Semester 2018-2019 Stat-610: Experimental Design-II Stat-703: Design and Analysis of Experiments for Researchers Stat-712: Theory of Experimental Design  Summer Semester 2017-2018 Stat-703: Design and Analysis of Experiments for Researchers  Spring Semester 2017-2018 Stat-705: Advanced Design of Experiments Stat-703: Design and Analysis of Experiments for Researchers Stat-609: Experimental Design-I     Winter Semester 2018-2019 Stat-610: Experimental Design-II   pdf Syllabus  Learning Objectives</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
