<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hadwiger function on Muhammad Yaseen</title>
    <link>https://myaseen208.com/tags/hadwiger-function/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hadwiger function on Muhammad Yaseen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myaseen208.com/tags/hadwiger-function/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Fertility Patterns of Pakistan during 1984-2007</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_zakria/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2013_zakria/</guid>
      <description>Modelling fertility patterns of a population has gained popularity among the demographers in recent years. This article investigates the fertility patterns of Pakistan and its urban and rural regions. The analysis of age specific fertility rates (ASFRs) has demonstrated high fertility in rural population as compared to urban and overall Pakistan population during the period 1984-2007. Substantial respective decreases of 44.98%, 48.72% and 46.76% in total fertility rates (TFRs) of rural, urban and overall Pakistan have been observed during the past 23 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the Age Specific Fertility Rates of Rural and Urban Areas of Pakistan During 1984-2007</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_modelingage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2012_modelingage/</guid>
      <description>This paper investigates the fertility pattern of Pakistan and its major breakdown rural and urban areas. The analysis of the age specific fertility rates (ASFRs) illustrated the greater fertility in the rural population as compared to the urban and of Pakistan population during the period 1984-2007. Approximately, 44.98% decrease in total fertility rate (TFR) of urban population during the past 23 years has been seen whereas 48.72% and 46.76% decrease in TFR of urban area and of Pakistan respectively with reference to the 1984.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>