<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time Use on Muhammad Yaseen</title>
    <link>https://myaseen208.com/tags/time-use/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time Use on Muhammad Yaseen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myaseen208.com/tags/time-use/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Pensioners and their Time Use: A Case Study of District Rahimyar Khan, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_qasim/</guid>
      <description>The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing. All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Time Use of Nurses and Paramedical Staff, Working in Public Hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan, Bahawalpur, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_gul/</guid>
      <description>The aim of the present study was to identify the drivers of inefficiencies existent in nurses&amp;rsquo; and paramedics&amp;rsquo; work and to detect the factors liable for decline in this profession, especially nursing. All the public sector hospitals of District Rahim Yar Khan were included in the study. A sample of size 118 was selected from the population of 1296 nurses and paramedics by the stratified random sampling technique. The analysis was done in R-programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen application accelerates the downy mildew disease severity with leaf age in canola plants</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_haq/</guid>
      <description>Downy mildew is a devastating disease of canola. Two years study was conducted to find the impact of different nitrogen levels on disease severity of downy mildew with respect to leaf age on canola plants in field conditions. Three nitrogen levels (11.50???Kg acre???1, 23???Kg acre???1 and 34.5???Kg acre???1) were applied in soil when plants were 40???days old. In control, 0???Kg acre???1 N was applied. The diseased leaves from the lower, middle and upper part of the plant were tagged and data were recorded after 10?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The level of Cry1Ac endotoxin and its efficacy against H. armigera in Bt cotton at large scale in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myaseen208.com/publications/2021_jamil/</guid>
      <description>A biophysical survey was conducted in 15 cotton-growing districts of Pakistan. Four hundred cotton growers were approached and inquired about the production technology of Bt cotton. Further, 25 strip tests using combo strips (Cry1Ac, Cry2Ab, Vip3Aa and Cp4, EPSPS gene) were performed at each farmer&amp;rsquo;s field. Out of 10,000 total-tested samples, farmers claimed 9682 samples as Bt and 318 samples as non-Bt. After performing a strip test, 1009 and 87 samples were found false negative and false positive, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
